<?xml version='1.0'?>
<help>
    <entry id="compose-actions">
        <title>Compose: Actions</title>
        <para>
            &quot;Send Message&quot; transmits your e-mail message to the recipient(s). Make sure you want to send your message as this action is final and cannot be reversed.
        </para>
        <para>
            &quot;Save Draft&quot; places an unfinished message in a drafts mailbox, accessible through any folder list. You can then finish the message later by switching to the drafts mailbox, clicking on the saved message to open it, and then clicking on &quot;Resume&quot;.
        </para>
        <tip>
            Entering a Subject in the e-mail before saving as a draft will allow you to more easily identify later which message you want to resume within the drafts mailbox.
        </tip>
        <para>
            &quot;Cancel Message&quot; drops the compose message in progress and, if composing in a non-popup window, returns you to the last mailbox you were viewing.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="compose-identity">
        <title>Compose: Identity</title>
        <para>
            Choose the identity to send e-mail as from a drop-down list of identities that you entered under Preferences-&gt;Personal Information.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="compose-to">
        <title>Compose: To</title>
        <para>
            Enter the correct e-mail address for the recipient(s) of your message. To enter multiple recipients, separate the e-mail addresses with commas (,).
        </para>
        <warn>
            Do NOT separate e-mail addresses with semicolons (;).
        </warn>
    </entry>

    <entry id="compose-cc">
        <title>Compose: Cc</title>
        <para>
            Enter the correct e-mail address for the carbon copy recipient(s) of your message. To enter multiple recipients, separate the e-mail addresses with commas (,).
        </para>
        <warn>
            Do NOT separate e-mail addresses with semicolons (;).
        </warn>
        <para>
            Carbon copies are usually sent to recipients who need not be the direct recipients of the message, but may need to receive the message for their information, usually indirectly concerned about the subject of the e-mail. All &quot;To:&quot; recipients and &quot;Cc:&quot; recipients can see the entire list of both kinds of recipients.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="compose-bcc">
        <title>Compose: Bcc</title>
        <para>
            Enter the correct e-mail address for the blind carbon copy recipient(s) of your message. To enter multiple recipients, separate the e-mail addresses with commas (,).
        </para>
        <warn>
            Do NOT separate e-mail addresses with semicolons (;).
        </warn>
        <para>
            Blind carbon copies are usually sent to recipients who may need to read what is being written WITHOUT the other recipients knowing that they are receiving the e-mail. Thus &quot;blind&quot; means that the identity of these recipients is hidden from all other recipients of the e-mail. Only you (as the sender) and the &quot;Bcc&quot; recipients will know that they received a copy.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="compose-subject">
        <title>Compose: Subject</title>
        <para>
            Enter the subject of your message. It is best to keep the subject short, simple and descriptive. The subject line is the easiest way for you and your correspondents to remember what was in the e-mail, and is generally used as the basis for quickly scanning e-mails in a mailbox.
        </para>
        <para>
            When you &quot;Reply&quot; or &quot;Forward&quot; an e-mail, this subject line is copied over into the new message so that is becomes a valuable way of identifying which messages go together to form a &quot;thread&quot; to an e-mail conversation.
        </para>
        <tip>
            If a replied or forwarded message contains new ideas, you may want to alter the &quot;Subject&quot; line so that recipients can follow the progression of the &quot;thread&quot; and to indicate that the content of the thread has deviated from the initial topic.
        </tip>
    </entry>

    <entry id="compose-spellcheck">
        <title>Compose: Spell Check</title>
        <warn>
            This action may not be available if your administrator has disabled it.
        </warn>
        <para>
            Click &quot;Spell Check&quot; to check your spelling. Incorrectly spelled words will be indicated in red and will be underlined; clicking on this word will reveal a list of suggested replacements. Click on a replacement word to replace in your original message, or click anyhere else to close the popup. When done spell checking, click on the &quot;Resume Editing&quot; button to continue editing your message.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="compose-sentmail">
        <title>Compose: Save Sent Mail</title>
        <warn>
            This action may not be available if your administrator has disabled it.
        </warn>
        <para>
            To keep a copy of the message you send, activate the checkbox next to &quot;Save&quot;. The destination mailbox will default to the mailbox selected for this purpose under &quot;Options-&gt;Personal Information-&gt;Identities&quot;. Your administrator may also allow selection of an alternate sent mail destination chosen via a drop-down list located next to this option.
        </para>
        <para>
            Saving copies of important e-mails you send could be useful for record keeping of what was discussed. This feature can be activated by default by going to &quot;Options-&gt;Personal Information-&gt;Edit your identities&quot;. In your options you can also setup maintenance tasks that empty or rename these sent mail mailboxes periodically.
        </para>
        <tip>
            You may not want to save every e-mail since you could have problems with your disk storage quota being used up quickly, especially when you send large attachments. A mailbox with full storage quota will not be able to receive new incoming e-mail.
        </tip>
    </entry>

    <entry id="compose-priority">
        <title>Compose: Priority</title>
        <para>
            This sets the message priority on your outgoing message. The priority tag is a pseudo-standard that most major e-mail clients can handle. Mail clients that do not handle this header will ignore it.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="filter-edit-rules">
        <title>Filters: Preferences: Edit Filter Rules</title>
        <para>
            Click &quot;Edit your filter rules&quot; to access the page where you can add, delete, and edit the currently active set of filter rules.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="filter-edit-blacklist">
        <title>Filters: Preferences: Edit Blacklist</title>
        <para>
            Click on &quot;Edit your blacklist&quot; to access the page where you can add, delete, and edit the list of e-mail addresses you ALWAYS refuse mail from.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="filter-edit-whitelist">
        <title>Filters: Preferences: Edit Whitelist</title>
        <para>
            Click on &quot;Edit your whitelist&quot; to access the page where you can add, delete, and edit the list of e-mail addresses you ALWAYS accept mail from.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="filter-on-login">
        <title>Filters: Preferences: Filter on Login</title>
        <para>
            Check this option to always apply filters when first logging on.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="filter-on-display">
        <title>Filters: Preferences: Filter on Refresh</title>
        <para>
            Check this option to always apply filters whenever you view the Inbox.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="filter-any-mailbox">
        <title>Filters: Preferences: Filter any Mailbox</title>
        <para>
            Check this option if you want to be allowed to apply filter rules to any mailbox. Normally, filtering rules are only applied to new mail that is delivered to your Inbox. If this option is checked, an icon will appear on all mailbox pages that will allow you to apply filter rules to the messages in the current mailbox.
        </para>
        <tip>
            Filtering in mailboxes other than Inbox may produce strange (e.g. the filter may cause a copy of messages to be delivered to the same mailbox) and/or undesired results (e.g. it may cause messages to be moved/deleted if new filtering rules have been implemented since the message has been delivered to the current mailbox).
        </tip>
    </entry>

    <entry id="pgp-compose-attach-pubkey">
        <title>PGP: Preferences: Attach Public Key</title>
        <para>
            If selected then a copy of your PGP public key, if it exists, will be attached to the outgoing message. You can set the default behavior via the PGP Preferences screen.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="pgp-option-reply-pubkey">
        <title>PGP: Preferences: Validate PGP Public Keys When Replying</title>
        <para>
            If set, and PGP encryption is used by default for composing messages, all of the recipients' public keys will be verified when the reply is first created. This has the disadvantage that it may cause a noticeable delay in opening the reply window. Conversely, it has the advantage of informing you immediately if you will be unable to correctly send the encrypted message to all recipients.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="compose-options-encrypt">
        <title>Compose: Encryption Options</title>
        <heading>No Encryption</heading>
        <para>
            Send the message with no encryption (cleartext).
        </para>
        <heading>PGP Encrypt Message</heading>
        <para>
            This option will encrypt the current message, using PGP and the recipients personal public key, and then send it. You MUST have the public key of the recipient stored in your addressbook or else this option will fail. If you have the public key for the recipient in your addressbook and are still receiving errors, verify that the e-mail address in the recipient field matches the e-mail address where the public key is stored. The encrypted data will be attached to the outgoing message.
        </para>
        <heading>PGP Sign Message</heading>
        <para>
            This option will digitally sign the current message using PGP and your personal private key. If you have not already entered the passphrase for your private key during this session you will be prompted for it. The recipient must have a copy of your public key to digitally verify your signature.
        </para>
        <heading>PGP Sign/Encrypt Message</heading>
        <para>
            This option will first digitally sign your message and then will encrypt the resulting output. See the &quot;PGP Encrypt Message&quot; and &quot;PGP Sign Message&quot; entries for further information.
        </para>
        <heading>PGP Encrypt Message with passphrase</heading>
        <para>
            This option will encrypt the current message, using PGP and a passphrase, and then send it. You will be prompted for the passphrase that should be used for the encryption. Give the passphrase to the recipient through a secure channel (e.g. personal conversation, phone). The encrypted data will be attached to the outgoing message.
        </para>
        <heading>PGP Sign/Encrypt Message with passphrase</heading>
        <para>
            This option will first digitally sign your message and then will encrypt the resulting output with a passphrase. See the &quot;PGP Encrypt Message with passphrase&quot; and &quot;PGP Sign Message&quot; entries for further information.
        </para>
        <heading>S/MIME Encrypt Message</heading>
        <para>
            This option will encrypt the current message, using S/MIME and the recipient's certificate, and then send it. You MUST have the certificate of the recipient stored in your addressbook or else this option will fail. If you have the certificate for the recipient in your addressbook and are still receiving errors, verify that the e-mail address in the recipient field matches the e-mail address where the certificate is stored. The encrypted data will be attached to the outgoing message.
        </para>
        <heading>S/MIME Sign Message</heading>
        <para>
            This option will digitally sign the current message using S/MIME and your certificate. If you have not already entered the passphrase for your certificate during this session you will be prompted for it.
        </para>
        <heading>S/MIME Sign/Encrypt Message</heading>
        <para>
            This option will first digitally sign your message and then will encrypt the resulting output. See the &quot;S/MIME Encrypt Message&quot; and &quot;S/MIME Sign Message&quot; entries for further information.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="pgp-overview">
        <title>PGP: Overview</title>
        <heading>What is PGP?</heading>
        <para>
            PGP is a tool for secure communication and data storage, especially for use with e-mail. It can be used to encrypt data and to create digital signatures. GnuPG (GNU Privacy Guard) is used to provide this functionality.
        </para>
        <heading>Enable PGP functionality?</heading>
        <para>
            If this option is selected, you will be able to create/view your personal PGP keys, add/delete public keys from other individuals, read encrypted mail, verify digitally signed mail, and encrypt/sign your outgoing mail.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="pgp-option-attach-pubkey">
        <title>PGP: Preferences: Attach Public Key</title>
        <para>
            If selected then a copy of your PGP public key, if it exists, will be attached to all outgoing messages.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="pgp-manage-pubkey">
        <title>PGP: Preferences: Manage Public Keys</title>
        <heading>Overview</heading>
        <para>
            This section lists all of the current users in your addressbook that have PGP public keys. These users are the ONLY users that you can either 1) send an encrypted message to -OR- 2) verify a digital signature.
        </para>
        <heading>View</heading>
        <para>
            Opens a window to view the PGP public key.
        </para>
        <heading>Details</heading>
        <para>
            Displays some details about the PGP public key.
        </para>
        <heading>Delete</heading>
        <para>
            Deletes the public key from your addressbook.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="pgp-import-pubkey">
        <title>PGP: Preferences: Manage Public Keys: Import</title>
        <para>
            This button will open a window where you can manually import a PGP public key. The key can either be pasted into a textfield or, if the key resides in a file on your local computer, you can import it. If the key is valid it will be inserted into your addressbook and the window will close; if not valid, an error message will be returned explaining why.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="pgp-overview-personalkey">
        <title>PGP: Preferences: Manage Personal Keys</title>
        <heading>Overview</heading>
        <para>
            If you want to digitally sign messages or enable others to send you encrypted messages, you must have your own personal public/private PGP keypair.
        </para>
        <heading>Your Public Key</heading>
        <para>
            Your public key should be made available to any person that you want to be able to send you encrypted messages that only YOU can decrypt (using your private key). Additionally, your public key needs to be made available to anybody you send a digitally signed message to - a public key is required to verify the digital signature.
        </para>
        <heading>Your Private Key</heading>
        <para>
            Your private key is necessary to decrypt any message encrypted using your public key. Additionally, your private key is needed if you want to digitally sign a message. Your private key will be protected via a passphrase created when the keys are generated. Thus, to perform any activity that requires your private key, you will be prompted for your passphrase. Entry of your passphrase is only needed once per session.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="pgp-personalkey-public">
        <title>PGP: Preferences: Manage Personal Keys: Public Key</title>
        <heading>View</heading>
        <para>
            Opens a window to view the PGP public key.
        </para>
        <heading>Details</heading>
        <para>
            Displays some details about the PGP public key.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="pgp-personalkey-private">
        <title>PGP: Preferences: Manage Personal Keys: Private Key</title>
        <heading>Enter Passphrase</heading>
        <para>
            Opens the passphrase dialog window. The passphrase entered, if correct, will be stored until your session ends.
        </para>
        <heading>Unload Passphrase</heading>
        <para>
            Removes the stored passphrase. Any additional usage of the private key will require you to re-enter the passphrase.
        </para>
        <heading>View</heading>
        <para>
            Opens a window to view the PGP private key. DO NOT SEND THIS KEY TO ANYONE. This option exists only so that you can export your personal private key for use in another program.
        </para>
        <heading>Details</heading>
        <para>
            Displays some technical details about the PGP private key.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="pgp-personalkey-delete">
        <title>PGP: Preferences: Manage Personal Keys: Delete</title>
        <para>
            This button will delete your personal public/private keypair.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="pgp-personalkey-create-name">
        <title>PGP: Preferences: Create Personal Key: Name</title>
        <para>
            The name you want embedded in your personal keys. A required field.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="pgp-personalkey-create-comment">
        <title>PGP: Preferences: Create Personal Key: Comment</title>
        <para>
        A comment string you want embedded in your personal keys. An optional field.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="pgp-personalkey-create-email">
        <title>PGP: Preferences: Create Personal Key: E-mail Address</title>
        <para>
            The e-mail address you want associated with your personal keys. A required field.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="pgp-personalkey-create-passphrase">
        <title>PGP: Preferences: Create Personal Key: Passphrase</title>
        <para>
            The passphrase used to protect/encrypt your personal private key. This should be AT LEAST 6 characters, should NOT be the same as your login password, should NOT be based on a dictionary word, and should include both numbers and letters. You must enter this passphrase twice for verification purposes. A required field.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="pgp-personalkey-create-actions">
        <title>PGP: Preferences: Create Personal Key: Actions</title>
        <heading>Create Key</heading>
        <para>
            Create and store your personal key.
        </para>
        <heading>Import Key</heading>
        <para>
            This button opens a window where you can manually import your existing PGP personal key. The key can either be pasted into a textfield or, if the key resides in a file on your local computer, can be uploaded. If the key is valid it will be inserted into your preferences and the window will close; if not valid, an error message will be returned explaining why.
        </para>
        <para>
            Only the private portion of your key is needed; the public key will be automatically generated from the private key.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="smime-overview">
        <title>S/MIME: Overview</title>
        <heading>What is S/MIME?</heading>
        <para>
            S/MIME is a private/public key pair system which provides digital signatures, message privacy, and tamper detection in an open, interoperable way. S/MIME can provide message privacy by encrypting messages that only the sender and the intended recipients can decode. It allows you to identify the sender of a message via a digital signature. Together, this encryption and digital signing help provide tamper detection, allowing recipients to determine whether a message was altered after it was sent.
        </para>
        <heading>Enable S/MIME functionality?</heading>
        <para>
            If this option is selected, you will be able to import your personal S/MIME keys, read encrypted mail, verify digitally signed mail, and encrypt/sign your outgoing mail.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="smime-overview-personalkey">
        <title>S/MIME: Preferences: Personal Certificates</title>
        <para>
            If you want to digitally sign or encrypt messages you must have your own personal public/private S/MIME certificates.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="smime-import-personal-certs">
        <title>S/MIME: Preferences: Personal Certificates: Import</title>
        <para>
            Import personal certificates from a PKCS #12 format file. PKCS #12 files are usually generated when exporting a key from a browser (e.g. Internet Explorer, Firefox) or from a certificate store maintained by an Operating System (e.g. Windows). If the keys are valid they will be inserted into your preferences and the window will close; if not valid, an error message will be returned explaining the problem.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="smime-delete-personal-certs">
        <title>S/MIME: Preferences: Personal Certificates: Delete</title>
        <para>
            Delete your personal certificates from your preferences.  You will no longer be able to sign S/MIME messages or view any S/MIME encrypted messages addressed to you.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="smime-manage-pubkey">
        <title>S/MIME: Preferences: Manage Public Keys</title>
        <para>
            Manage your S/MIME public key list.
        </para>
        <heading>View</heading>
        <para>
            View the raw text of the public key.
        </para>
        <heading>Details</heading>
        <para>
            View technical details of the public key.
        </para>
        <heading>Delete</heading>
        <para>
            Deletes the selected public key from storage.  Deleting a public key for a user will prevent you from encrypting a message to that user.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="printing">
        <title>Message: Printing</title>
        <para>
            To print a message you are viewing, click on the &quot;Print&quot; icon located next to the part of the message you want to print. The message will open in a new window formated for printing. Depending on your web browser and operating system, the print dialog box may open for you. If it does not open, then pull down the web browser's &quot;File&quot; menu and choose &quot;Print&quot; to open the print dialog box.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="sorting">
        <title>Mailbox: Sorting and Threading</title>
        <heading>Sorting Entries</heading>
        <para>
            When viewing a list of messages, you can sort the messages by any column by clicking on the appropriate column heading. To switch columns between ascending and descending order, click on the arrow icon in the column heading.
        </para>
        <heading>Threading</heading>
        <para>
            The subject field can be sorted either alphabeticaly or by threading - messages that are all related to each other.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="prefs-rename_sentmail_monthly">
        <title>Compose: Sent Mail: Preferences: Rename Sent Mail Folder Monthly</title>
        <para>
            Turn this preference on if you would like to rename your sent mail folder at the beginning of every month. The folder will be renamed (to a name that contains the month and year) and a new sent mail folder will be created.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="prefs-delete_sentmail_monthly_keep">
        <title>Compose: Sent Mail: Preferences: Delete Sent Mail Folder Monthly</title>
        <para>
            This option will purge old sent mail folders after a given number of months.  Any folders older than this value will be deleted.  This may be useful if you have a quota, for example.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="prefs-purge_sentmail_interval">
        <title>Compose: Sent Mail: Preferences: Purge Sent Mail</title>
        <para>
            How often should your sent mail folder(s) be purged?
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="prefs-purge_sentmail_keep">
        <title>Compose: Sent Mail: Preferences: Purge Sent Mail Keep</title>
        <para>
            If you are purging your sent mail folder(s), message older than how many days should be purged?
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="prefs-delete_attachments_monthly_keep">
        <title>Compose: Preferences: Delete Linked Attachments Monthly</title>
        <para>
            If your local account is configured to allow sending linked attachments in outgoing compose messages, this option will purge old linked attachments after a given number of months.  Any attachments older than this value will be deleted.  This may be useful if you have a quota, for example.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="prefs-purge_trash_interval">
        <title>Login Tasks: Preferences: Purge Trash</title>
        <para>
            How often should your trash folder be purged?
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="prefs-purge_trash_keep">
        <title>Login Tasks: Preferences: Purge Trash Keep</title>
        <para>
            If you are purging your trash folder, message older than how many days should be purged?
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="prefs-purge_spam_interval">
        <title>Login Tasks: Preferences: Purge Spam</title>
        <para>
            How often should your spam folder be purged?
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="prefs-purge_spam_keep">
        <title>Login Tasks: Preferences: Purge Spam Keep</title>
        <para>
            If you are purging your spam folder, message older than how many days should be purged?
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="prefs-attrib_text">
        <title>Compose: Preferences: Attribution Text</title>
        <para>
            Here you can enter the phrase that you wish to appear before any quoted text in a reply that you send.
        </para>
        <para>
            You can include one or more special placeholders to insert information about the message to which you are replying. Placeholders consist of a &apos;%&apos; followed by a single letter. The following placeholders are available:
        </para>
        <raw>
            %f : The sender&apos;s name and email address
        </raw>
        <raw>
            %a : The sender&apos;s email address
        </raw>
        <raw>
            %p : The sender&apos;s name
        </raw>
        <raw>
            %r : The full RFC 822/2822/5322 style date and time zone
        </raw>
        <raw>
            %d : The date as www, dd mmm YYYY
        </raw>
        <raw>
            %x : The date in the locale&apos;s default
        </raw>
        <raw>
            %c : The date and time in the locale&apos;s default
        </raw>
        <raw>
            %m : The Message-ID
        </raw>
        <raw>
            %s : The subject
        </raw>
         <raw>
            %n : A new line
        </raw>
        <raw>
            %% : The &apos;%&apos; character
        </raw>
    </entry>

    <entry id="prefs-default_msg_charset">
        <title>Message: Preferences: Default Message Character Set</title>
        <para>
            Define the default character set to use for text message parts that do not contain explicit character set information. Per the MIME e-mail standard, messages send without character set information must be displayed using the basic 'US-ASCII' character set. However, certain badly broken mailers may send out text messages in other character sets without setting the proper parameters in the message header. Set this parameter to the default character set string to use locally. Select &quot;Default&quot; to use the MIME defaults.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="prefs-request_mdn">
        <title>Compose: Preferences: Request Read Receipts</title>
        <para>
            &quot;Request a Read Receipt&quot; sends a read receipt request (also known as a Message Dispositon Notification) to the recipients of a composed message to notify you when this message is opened by the recipients. Not all clients support / honor this.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="prefs-send_mdn">
        <title>Message: Preferences: Send Read Receipt</title>
        <para>
            &quot;Send a Read Receipt&quot; sends a read receipt (also known as a Message Disposition Notification) when you view a message in which the user has requested that they receive notification that you have read the message. By default, you will be prompted to send the notification.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="prefs-delete_spam_after_report">
        <title>Message: Preferences: Delete Spam After Reporting</title>
        <para>
            You may elect to do one of three items after reporting a message as spam.
        </para>
        <para>
            1. Do nothing. The message will be reported as spam but will otherwise remain unchanged in your mailbox.
        </para>
        <para>
            2. If reporting a message as spam, the message will be immediately deleted.
        </para>
        <para>
            3. After reporting a message as spam the message will be deleted from the current mailbox and moved to your spam folder.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="prefs-move_innocent_after_report">
        <title>Message: Preferences: Move Spam After Reporting As Innocent</title>
        <para>
            You may elect to do one of two items after reporting a message previously marked as spam as innocent.
        </para>
        <para>
            1. Do nothing. The message will be reported as innocent but will otherwise remain unchanged in your mailbox.
        </para>
        <para>
            2. If reporting a message as innocent the message will be deleted from the current mailbox and moved to your Inbox.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="prefs-image_replacement">
        <title>Message: Preferences: Image Replacement</title>
        <para>
            For messages displayed inline (i.e. on the message view page), should all image tags be blocked until you specifically decide to view those images? Note that, if explicitly viewing the attachment, images will always be displayed.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="prefs-save_attachments">
        <title>Compose: Sent Mail: Preferences: Save Attachments on Sent Messages</title>
        <para>
            If saving a composed message in a sent mail folder, determine if attachment data is saved by default.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="virtual_inbox">
        <title>Folders: Virtual Inbox</title>
        <para>
            Virtual Inbox is a saved search that does away with the need to search every mailbox for messages marked as new.  Instead, all currently subscribed mailboxes are searched for new messages and the results are displayed in a single mailbox.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <entry id="virtual_trash">
        <title>Folders: Virtual Trash</title>
        <para>
        Virtual Trash is a saved search that does away with the need for a separate Trash folder.  Instead of moving messages to a centralized trash folder, messages are simply marked as deleted in the current folder they live in.  When 'show deleted messages' is turned off, this results in these messages not appearing in a mailbox view.  When a user clicks on Virtual Trash, *all* mailboxes are searched for messages that are flagged deleted and these messages are displayed in a single mailbox.
        </para>
    </entry>

    <view id="basic">
        <entry id="mailbox-keyboard">
            <title>Mailbox: Keyboard Shortcuts</title>
            <para>
                You can use your keyboard to select and view messages in your mailbox. In order to move between messages, use the <css class="iconImg keyupImg"></css> and <css class="iconImg keydownImg"></css>keys while holding the <css class="kbd">Ctrl</css> key. You will start at the bottom of the page (last displayed message) if you press <css class="iconImg keyupImg"></css> and at the top of the page (first displayed message) if you press <css class="iconImg keydownImg"></css>.
            </para>
            <para>
                The current message is highlighted just as if you were mousing over it. While you are moving up and down through the mailbox list, you can press <css class="kbd">Space</css> to select or deselect that message, and you can press <css class="kbd">Enter</css> to view that message.
            </para>
            <para>
                If you are holding <css class="kbd">Alt</css> instead of <css class="kbd">Ctrl</css> while navigating through the mailbox, the messages you are passing are automatically selected or deselected.
            </para>
            <para>
                Use the <css class="iconImg keyleftImg"></css> and <css class="iconImg keyrightImg"></css> keys on your keyboard to go to the previous page of messages in your mailbox or the next page of messages.
            </para>
        </entry>

        <entry id="message-keyboard">
            <title>Message: Previous/Next Message</title>
            <para>
                Use the <css class="iconImg keyleftImg"></css> and <css class="iconImg keyrightImg"></css> keys on your keyboard to go to the previous message or the next message.
            </para>
        </entry>

        <entry id="compose-attachments">
            <title>Compose: Adding Attachments</title>
            <para>
                You may attach files to your message if your browser supports uploading of files.
            </para>
            <para>
                Click the &quot;Browse&quot; button and select the file to be attached. An additional upload input will appear, if you have not exceed your limit for the number of attachments allowed in a message, for uploading additional attachments.
            </para>
            <para>
                If you want to change the description, you can click the &quot;Update&quot; button to upload your attachments immediately and save any other changes you've made to existing attachments.
            </para>
            <tip>
                Please note that for large files and/or slower Internet connections, the process of uploading and attaching your file to the e-mail may take some time.
            </tip>
        </entry>

        <entry id="compose-current-attachments">
            <title>Compose: Current Attachments</title>
            <heading>Current Attachments</heading>
            <para>
                This section displays a list of files already attached to your message.
            </para>
            <heading>Delete Attachments</heading>
            <para>
                To delete an attached file(s):
            </para>
            <para>
                Step 1: Activate the check-button next to the attached filename(s) you want to delete.
            </para>
            <para>
                Step 2: Either click the &quot;Update&quot; button above the Current Attachments section to immediately view changes or the changes will automatically be performed when the message is sent.
            </para>
            <heading>Change Attachment Description</heading>
            <para>
                To change the description for your attachments (the text the recipient will see that describes the attachment):
            </para>
            <para>
                Step 1: Enter a description into the Description field.
            </para>
            <para>
                Step 2: Either click the &quot;Update&quot; button above the Current Attachments section to immediately view changes or the changes will automatically be performed when the message is sent.
            </para>
        </entry>

        <entry id="compose-link-attachments">
            <title>Compose: Link Attachments</title>
            <para>
                Determines whether the attachments in your composition are sent as a part of the mail message or whether those attachments are kept on a local server.  If attachments are linked, the recipient(s) of your message will be provided a web link where they can download the attachment(s).
            </para>
            <para>
                Linking attachments has the advantage of reducing the size of outgoing messages, especially for large attachments.  Linking attachments has the disadvantage that the content of the attachments cannot be guaranteed to be available in the future since the attachment data is not located within the e-mail message itself.
            </para>
        </entry>

        <entry id="folders">
            <title>Folders</title>
            <para>
                You can select folders by using the buttons along the left column. Once you have done this, select the action you wish to perform on the folders via the select box to the left.
            </para>
        </entry>

        <entry id="folders-create">
            <title>Folders: Create</title>
            <para>
                Create a new folder, if possible. To create a folder in the base level, select 'Create' without selecting a folder in the left column. To create a subfolder in a currently existing folder, select the existing folder in the left column before selecting 'Create'.
            </para>
        </entry>

        <entry id="folders-rename">
            <title>Folders: Rename</title>
            <para>
                Rename a folder. To rename, select the folders in the left column to rename and click 'Rename'. When renaming, all subfolders will automatically be renamed.
            </para>
        </entry>

        <entry id="folders-delete">
            <title>Folders: Delete</title>
            <para>
                Delete a folder and all messages inside the folder. To delete, select the folders in the left column to delete and click 'Delete'. When deleting a folder with children, these subfolders will not be automatically deleted. To remove these children, you must manually select all folders to delete using the left column.
            </para>
        </entry>

        <entry id="folders-empty">
            <title>Folders: Empty</title>
            <para>
                To delete all messages inside a folder, but not delete the folder itself, select the folders in the left column and click 'Empty'.
            </para>
        </entry>

        <entry id="folders-purge">
            <title>Folders: Purge</title>
            <para>
                To delete all messages inside a folder marked as deleted, but not delete the folder itself, select the folders in the left column and click 'Purge'. This option only appears if not using a trash folder.
            </para>
        </entry>

        <entry id="folders-subscribe">
            <title>Folders: Subscribe/Unsubscribe</title>
            <para>
                Flags a folder as either subscribed or unsubscribed. When a folder is subscribed, it will appear in all drop down folder lists. These options only appear if using IMAP folder subscriptions.
            </para>
            <para>
                To subscribe, select the folders in the left column and click 'Subscribe'. To unsubscribe, select the folders in the left column and click 'Unsubscribe'.
            </para>
        </entry>

        <entry id="folders-newmail">
            <title>Folders: Check for New Mail/Do Not Check for New Mail</title>
            <warn>
                This action may not be available if your administrator has disabled it.
            </warn>
            <para>
                Flags a folder to be checked for new mail in the Folder Navigator and the sidebar.
            </para>
            <para>
                To set this flag, select the folders in the left column to check and click 'Check for New Mail'. To unset this flag, select the folders in the left column to check and click 'Do Not Check for New Mail'.
            </para>
        </entry>

        <entry id="folders-markseen">
            <title>Folders: Mark All Messages as Seen/Unseen</title>
            <para>
                To mark all messages in a folder as seen, select the folders in the left column and click 'Mark All Messages as Seen'. To mark all messages in a folder as unseen, select the folders in the left column and click 'Mark All Messages as Unseen'.
            </para>
        </entry>

        <entry id="folders-download">
            <title>Folders: Download</title>
            <para>
                To download all messages in a folder in a single file (mbox format), select the folder in the left column and click 'Download'. To download the file in ZIP compressed format, instead select 'Download [.zip format].
            </para>
        </entry>

        <entry id="folders-import">
            <title>Folders: Import Messages</title>
            <para>
                This option will import mbox format or .eml files into the folder of your choice. Choose one folder via the left column to import the messages into and then select this option. You will then be taken to a page that will prompt for the mbox or .eml file to import.
            </para>
        </entry>

        <entry id="folders-rebuild">
            <title>Folders: Rebuild Folder Tree</title>
            <para>
                Rebuild the graphical representation of the folder tree by requerying the mail server. You should not normally need to do this unless you are simultaneously accessing the mail server with another mail client and that mail client has made changes to the folder structure.
            </para>
        </entry>

        <entry id="folders-showsub">
            <title>Folders: Show/Hide Unsubscribed</title>
            <para>
                If using IMAP folder subscriptions, show/hide the unsubscribed folders. To subscribe/unsubscribe to a folder, select the checkbox next to the foldername and use the Subscribe/Unsubscribe action in the Folder Action drop-down menu.
            </para>
        </entry>

        <entry id="folders-expandall">
            <heading>Folders: Expand All</heading>
            <para>
                Expand all folder entries.
            </para>
        </entry>

        <entry id="folders-collapseall">
            <heading>Folders: Collapse All</heading>
            <para>
                Collapse all folder entries.
            </para>
        </entry>

        <entry id="filter-apply">
            <title>Filters: Apply Rules</title>
            <para>
                Click on the &quot;Apply Filter&quot; icon next to the Inbox name in the mailbox view to filter all messages according to the specified rules.
            </para>
        </entry>
    </view>

    <view id="dynamic">
        <entry id="compose-attachments">
            <title>Compose: Adding Attachments</title>
            <para>
                You may attach files to your message if your browser supports uploading of files.
            </para>
            <para>
                Click the &quot;Browse&quot; button and select the file to be attached. An additional upload input will appear, if you have not exceed your limit for the number of attachments allowed in a message, for uploading additional attachments.
            </para>
            <tip>
                Please note that for large files and/or slower Internet connections, the process of uploading and attaching your file to the e-mail may take some time.
            </tip>
        </entry>

        <entry id="compose-current-attachments">
            <title>Compose: Current Attachments</title>
            <heading>Viewing Attachments</heading>
            <para>
                If the attachment filename is clickable, the attachment data can be viewed in the browser. Click on the attachment name to view the contents of the attachment in a popup window.
            </para>
            <heading>Delete Attachments</heading>
            <para>
                To delete an attachment, click the &quot;Remove&quot; button next to the name of the attachment you want to delete
            </para>
        </entry>

        <entry id="mailbox">
            <title>Mailbox</title>
            <para>
                To preview a message, select it from the message list.
            </para>
            <para>
                A right-click on a message or a mailbox will display available actions.
            </para>
            <warn>
                Opera does not support right-click actions.  Instead, a left click + <css class="kbd">Shift</css> + <css class="kbd">Ctrl</css> will display available actions.
            </warn>
            <para>
                Click on a message while holding down the <css class="kbd">Ctrl</css> key to select multiple messages.  To select a range of messages, click the first message of the range, navigate to the last message of the range, and then click on the last message while holding down the <css class="kbd">Shift</css> key.
            </para>
        </entry>

        <entry id="mailbox-keyboard">
            <title>Mailbox: Keyboard Shortcuts</title>
            <para>
                The following keyboard shortcuts are available:
            </para>
            <para>
                <css class="iconImg keyupImg"></css> / <css class="iconImg keydownImg"></css> : Move up/down through the message list.
            </para>
            <para>
                <css class="kbd">PgUp</css> / <css class="kbd">PgDown</css> : Move one page up/down through the message list.
            </para>
            <para>
                <css class="kbd">Alt</css> + (<css class="kbd">PgUp</css> / <css class="kbd">PgDown</css> / <css class="iconImg keyupImg"></css> / <css class="iconImg keydownImg"></css>): Scroll up/down through the display of the previewed message.
            </para>
            <para>
                <css class="kbd">Home</css> / <css class="kbd">End</css> : Move to the beginning/end of the message list.
            </para>
            <para>
                <css class="kbd">Del</css> : Delete the currently selected message(s). <css class="kbd">Shift</css> + <css class="kbd">Del</css> will delete the current message and move to the next message if a single message is selected.
            </para>
            <para>
                <css class="kbd">Shift</css> + <css class="kbd">N</css> : Move to the next unseen message (non-search mailboxes only).
            </para>
            <para>
                <css class="kbd">Enter</css> : Open message in a popup window.
            </para>
            <para>
                <css class="kbd">Ctrl</css> + <css class="kbd">A</css> : Select all messages in the current mailbox.
            </para>
        </entry>
    </view>
</help>
