<?xml version='1.0'?>
<help>

<entry id="Overview">
    <title>Kronolith: Overview</title>
    <heading>What is Kronolith?</heading>
    <para>
    Kronolith is a web-based calendar application.  In addition to the
    required functions of creating, modifying, and deleting events, it
    currently supports recurring events (with exceptions and various deletion
    options), alarms, import and export functions (iCalendar and CSV formats),
    iCalendar invitations, multiple calendar views, shared calendars, display
    of Task List (Nag) tasks (if Tasks List is installed), and ability to show
    events in the Horde summary screen.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="menu-today">
    <title>Menu: Today</title>
    <para>
    The <i>Today</i> menu item will display your default view (month, week,
    day, etc. as set in Preferences) for the current date.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="menu-Goto">
    <title>Menu: Goto</title>
    <para>
    The <i>Goto</i> menu item will display a small pop-up window in which you
    can quickly select a month, week of the year, or day of the month to <i>go
    to</i>.  This is usually the quickest way to move within the calendar.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="menu-Day">
    <title>Menu: Day</title>
    <para>
    The <i>Day</i> tab will display the day view of the currently selected
    day.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="menu-work-week">
    <title>Menu: Work Week</title>
    <para>
    The <i>Work Week</i> tab will display the work week view (Monday through
    Friday) closest to the currently selected day.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="menu-week">
    <title>Menu: Week</title>
    <para>
    The <i>Week</i> tab will display the week view (7 day view) for the week
    containing the currently selected day.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="menu-month">
    <title>Menu: Month</title>
    <para>
    The <i>Month</i> tab will display the month view for the month containing
    the currenly selected day.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="menu-new-event">
    <title>Menu: New Event</title>
    <para>
    The <i>New Event</i> menu item will allow you to create a new event to be
    added to a calendar.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="menu-prefs">
    <title>Menu: Preferences</title>
    <para>
    The <i>Preferences</i> menu item allows you to set <i>Preferences</i> that
    control the look and feel of Kronolith, Kronolith's interaction with Horde
    and other Horde applications, and manage multiple and shared calendars.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="menu-import-export">
    <title>Menu: Import/Export</title>
    <para>
    The <i>Import/Export</i> menu item allows you to import or export calendar
    events.  Currently you can import files in CSV, Microsoft Outlook, and
    vCalendar/iCalendar formats.  You can export to only CSV and iCalendar
    formats.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="alarms">
    <title>Alarms</title>
    <para>
    Kronolith can generate alarms for events in a calendar.  By default, the
    first alarm is generated fifteen minutes before the appointment is
    supposed to start, but the alarm can be set (per event) to occur at almost
    any interval before the event start time.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="recurring-events">
    <title>Recurring Events</title>
    <para>
    Events can be made to repeat in various ways. Many events repeat in
    certain frequently used ways. For example, the <i>Monthly</i> recurrence
    types make the selected item repeat each month and the <i>Weekly</i>
    recurrence type makes the selected item repeat each per week. These can be
    made to represent events that repeat in complex ways: for example, an item
    that occurs on the third Friday of each month, or an item that occurs on
    Monday, Wednesday, and Friday every week.
    </para>
    <para>
    You can also restrict how long an event repeats by selecting the <i>end
    date</i> for the event's recurrence.
    </para>
    <para>
    Normally, a modification to a repeating event applies to all occurrences
    of that event. A single occurrence of a repeating event can be modified by
    editing the occurrence, removing its recurrence information, and then
    choosing the <i>Save as New</i> option from the Repeat menu. The selected
    occurrence can now be modified independently of the other occurences.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="Printing">
    <title>Printing</title>
    <heading>Printing Calendars and Events</heading>
    <para>
    Certain views are designed to be printable.  When in one of these views, a
    <i>Print</i> icon will appear in the top menu bar.  Use this menu icon to
    print the current view.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="shares">
  <title>Calendar Permissions</title>
  <para>
    Here should go a few explanations on the different users and groups that
    permissions can be assigned to.
  </para>
  <para>
    This should be a place to explain the different permission types and
    what they mean regarding to events and calendars.
  </para>
</entry>

<entry id="embed">
  <title>Embedding</title>
  <para>
    It is possible to embed small views of your calendars in external websites.
    You can embed the same views that you can place on Horde's portal page. The
    following are examples of code to use to embed each view on an external
    blog or website. You should obviously edit the code with the correct server
    address and calendar name.  The 'container' parameter is arbitrary, but must
    both match the DOM id of the the div element and be unique across the whole
    page you are embedding in.
  </para>
  <para>
    To embed a small Month View of the current month:
  </para>
    <i>&lt;div id=&quot;kronocalendar&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;script
    src=&quot;http://hostname.example.com/horde/kronolith/imple.php?imple=Embed
    /container=kronocalendar/view=month/calendar=calendar_name&quot;
    type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</i>
  <para>
    To embed an Upcoming Events View (note the 'months' and 'maxevents'
    parameters):
  </para>
    <i>&lt;div id=&quot;kronolist&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;script
    src=&quot;http://hostname.example.com/horde/kronolith/imple.php?imple=Embed
    /view=monthlist/calendar=calendar_name/container=kronolist/months=2/
    maxevents=10&quot; type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</i>
  <para>
    To embed a Summary View:
  </para>
    <i>&lt;div id=&quot;kronosummary&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;
    src=&quot;http://hostname.example.com/horde/kronolith/imple.php?imple=Embed
    /container=kronosummary/view=summary/calendar=calendar_name
    &quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;</i>
</entry>
</help>
