<?xml version='1.0'?>
<help>

<entry id="Overview">
    <title>Kronolith: Overview</title>
    <heading>What is Kronolith?</heading>
    <para>
    Kronolith is a web-based calendar application.  In addition to the required
    functions of creating, modifying, and deleting events, it currently
    supports dynamic and mobile interfaces, CalDAV clients, shared calendars,
    remote calendars, invitation management (iCalendar/iTip), free/busy
    management, resource management, alarms, recurring events, tasks
    integration (if the tasks application is installed), import and export
    functions (iCalendar and CSV formats), and a number of different calender
    views.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="menu-new-event">
    <title>Menu: New Event</title>
    <para>
    The &quot;New Event&quot; menu item will allow you to create a new event to
    be added to a calendar.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="menu-Day">
    <title>Menu: Day</title>
    <para>
    The &quot;Day&quot; tab will display the day view of the currently selected
    day.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="menu-work-week">
    <title>Menu: Work Week</title>
    <para>
    The &quot;Work Week&quot; tab will display the work week view (Monday
    through Friday) closest to the currently selected day.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="menu-week">
    <title>Menu: Week</title>
    <para>
    The &quot;Week&quot; tab will display the week view (7 day view) for the
    week containing the currently selected day.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="menu-month">
    <title>Menu: Month</title>
    <para>
    The &quot;Month&quot; tab will display the month view for the month
    containing the currenly selected day.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="menu-prefs">
    <title>Preferences</title>
    <para>
    The &quot;Preferences&quot; menu item allows you to set preferences that
    control the look and feel of Kronolith, Kronolith's interaction with Horde
    and other Horde applications.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="caldav">
    <title>CalDAV Clients</title>
    <para>
    CalDAV clients can directly access the internal calendars (and task lists)
    of Kronolith. External calendars like events provided by other applications
    or remote calendars are not provided to CalDAV clients.
    </para>
    <para>
    How to configure access to the calendars and which CalDAV URLs to use
    depends on the client. Below are a few examples on how to access CalDAV
    resources from common calendar clients:
    </para>
    <heading>Thunderbird/Lightning</heading>
    <para>
    Lightning, the calendar add-on to Thunderbird, requires to subscribe to
    each CalDAV calendar individually. In the &quot;File&quot; menu choose
    &quot;New&quot;, then &quot;Calendar&quot;. In the following dialogs choose
    &quot;On the Network&quot;, then &quot;CalDAV&quot;. Copy the &quot;CalDAV
    Subscription URL&quot; from the &quot;Subscription&quot; tab of Kronolith's
    calendar dialog into the &quot;Location&quot; field.
    </para>
    <heading>Apple iCal</heading>
    <para>
    CalDAV servers can be added in the &quot;Preferences&quot; dialog, at the
    &quot;Accounts&quot; tab. Click on the &quot;+&quot; button and choose
    &quot;CalDAV&quot; as the &quot;Account Type&quot; in the upcoming
    dialog. Enter your user name and password into the correct fields. Copy the
    &quot;CalDAV Account URL&quot; from the &quot;Subscription&quot; tab of
    Kronolith's calendar dialog into iCal's &quot;Server Address&quot; field.
    </para>
    <heading>Evolution</heading>
    <para>
    Evolution requires to subscribe to each CalDAV calendar individually. In
    the &quot;File&quot; menu choose &quot;New&quot;, then
    &quot;Calendar&quot;. Choose &quot;CalDAV&quot; as the &quot;Type&quot; in
    the upcoming dialog. Copy the server name of the &quot;CalDAV Subscription
    URL&quot; from the &quot;Subscription&quot; tab of Kronolith's calendar
    dialog into the &quot;Server&quot; field. Copy the path of the URL to the
    &quot;Path&quot; field. E.g. if your Subscription URL is
    &quot;http://www.example.com/rpc/calendars/user/calendar:xyz/&quot;, then
    copy &quot;www.example.com&quot; to the &quot;Server&quot; field and
    &quot;/rpc/calendars/user/calendar:xyz/&quot; to the path field.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="menu-import-export">
    <title>Import/Export</title>
    <para>
    The &quot;Import/Export&quot; menu item in the basic mode, or the
    &quot;Import&quot; and &quot;Export&quot; tabs in the dynamic view allow
    you to import or export calendar events.  Depending on the mode you can
    currently import and export files in CSV, Microsoft Outlook, or
    vCalendar/iCalendar formats.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="alarms">
    <title>Alarms</title>
    <para>
    Kronolith can generate alarms for events in a calendar. The alarm can be
    set (per event) to occur at almost any interval before the event start
    time.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="recurring-events">
    <title>Recurring Events</title>
    <para>
    Events can be made to repeat in various ways. Many events repeat in certain
    frequently used ways. For example, the &quot;Monthly&quot; recurrence types
    make the selected item repeat each month and the &quot;Weekly&quot;
    recurrence type makes the selected item repeat each per week. These can be
    made to represent events that repeat in complex ways: for example, an item
    that occurs on the third Friday of each month, or an item that occurs on
    Monday, Wednesday, and Friday every week.
    </para>
    <para>
    You can also restrict how long an event repeats by selecting the end date
    or a recurrence count for the event's recurrence.
    </para>
    <para>
    Normally, a modification to a repeating event applies to all occurrences of
    that event. A single occurrence of a repeating event can be modified by
    editing the occurrence, removing its recurrence information, and then
    choosing the &quot;Save as New&quot; option from the Repeat menu. The
    selected occurrence can now be modified independently of the other
    occurences.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="embed">
  <title>Embedding</title>
  <para>
    It is possible to embed small views of your calendars in external websites.
    You can embed the same views that you can place on Horde's portal page. The
    following are examples of code to use to embed each view on an external
    blog or website. You should obviously edit the code with the correct server
    address and calendar name.  The 'container' parameter is arbitrary, but must
    both match the DOM id of the the div element and be unique across the whole
    page you are embedding in.
  </para>
  <para>
    To embed a small Month View of the current month:
  </para>
  <raw>
    &lt;div id=&quot;kronocalendar&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;script
    src=&quot;http://hostname.example.com/horde/services/imple.php?imple=Embed/
    impleApp=kronolith/container=kronocalendar/view=month/calendar=calendar_name
    &quot;type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
  </raw>
  <para>
    To embed an Upcoming Events View (note the 'months' and 'maxevents'
    parameters):
  </para>
  <raw>
    &lt;div id=&quot;kronolist&quot;&gt;&lt;/div&gt;&lt;script
    src=&quot;http://hostname.example.com/horde/services/imple.php?imple=Embed/
    impleApp=kronolith/view=monthlist/calendar=calendar_name/container=kronolist/
    months=2/maxevents=10&quot; type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;&gt;&lt;/script
    &gt;
  </raw>
  <para>
    To embed a Summary View:
  </para>
  <raw>
    &lt;div id=&quot;kronosummary&quot;&gt;
    &lt;/div&gt;&lt;script type=&quot;text/javascript&quot;
    src=&quot;http://hostname.example.com/horde/services/imple.php?imple=Embed/
    impleApp=kronolith/container=kronosummary/view=summary/calendar=calendar_name
    &quot;&gt;&lt;/script&gt;
  </raw>
</entry>
</help>
