<?xml version="1.0" encoding="UTF-8"?>
<help>

<entry id="keyboard-navigation" state="new">
    <title>Klaviatūra: Navigācija</title>
    <para>Pastāv iespēja izmantot klaviatūru, lai pārvietotos sarakstā no vēstules uz vēstuli, uz iepriekšējo vai nākošo vēstuli, kamēr lasāt atvērto vēstuli vai pa pastkastes vēstuļu saraksta lappusēm.
      </para>
    <heading>Navigācija vēstuļu sarakstā</heading>
    <para>Varat izmantot klaviatūru, lai atzīmētu vai atvērtu lasīšanai vēstules no saraksta. Lai pārvietotos no vēstules uz vēstuli, izmantojiem pogas Augšup un Lejup, vienlaikus turot nospiestu Ctrl pogu. Jūs sāksiet saraksta lejas daļā (ar pēdējo lasīto vēstuli), ja nospiedīsiet Augšup vai saraksta augšā (pirmā lasītā vēstule), ja nospiedīsiet Lejup.</para>
    <para>Aktuālā vēstule tiek izcelta līdzīgi kā izmantojot peli. Pārvietojoties augšup vai lejup pa sarakstu, varat atzīmēt vēstules vai atcel atzīmēšanu, nospiežot Tukšuma pogu (Space) vai arī atvērt vēstuli lasīšanai, nospiežot pogu Enter.</para>
    <para>Ja pārvietojoties pa vēstuļu sarakstu, turēsiet nospiestu Alt, nevis Ctrl pogu, vēstules tiks automātiski iezīmētas (vai atcelts iezīmējums).</para>
    <heading>Vēstuļu saraksts: Iepriekšējā/Nākošā lapa</heading>
    <para>Izmantojiet pogas Pa labi un Pa kreisi lai pārvietotos uz iepriekšējo vai nākošo vēstuļu saraksta lapu.</para>
    <heading>Vēstules skats: Iepriekšējā/Nākošā vēstule</heading>
    <para>Izmantojiet pogas Pa labi un Pa kreisi lai pārvietotos uz iepriekšējo vai nākošo vēstuli.</para>
</entry>

<!--
<entry id="keyboard-shortcuts">
    <title>Keyboard: Shortcuts</title>
    <heading>Using Keyboard Shortcuts</heading>
</entry>
-->

<entry id="compose-buttons">
    <title>Vēstules rakstīšana: Darbības</title>
    <heading>Darbības</heading>
    <para>
    "Nosūtīt" nosūta sagatavoto vēstuli norādītajam (-iem) saņēmējam(-iem). Pirms nosūtīšanas pārliecinieties, vai tiešām vēlaties vēstuli nosūtīt, jo atsaukt to nebūs iespējams.
    </para>
    <para>
    "Saglabāt Melnrakstu" saglabā vēstules melnrakstu mapē ar nosaukumu "Melnraksti", kurai var piekļūt no izkrītošās izvēlnes navigācijas joslas labajā pusē. Jūs varat pabeigt vēstuli vēlāk, pārslēdzoties uz mapi "Melnraksti", uzklikšķinot attiecīgajai vēstulei un "Atsākt". Pirms pierakstāt melnrakstu, pārliecinieties, vai esat norādījuši tematu - tas vēlāk palīdzēs vieglāk orientēties melnrakstu mapē.
    </para>
    <tip>
    Atkarībā no sistēmas iestatījumiem, Jums var būt iespēja noteikt vai pēc melnraksta saglabāšanas atgiezties mapē, kurā bijāt pirms tam vai arī pie pēdējās atvērtās vēstules.
    </tip>
    <para>
    "Pārtraukt" pārtrauc vēstules rakstīšanu, nesaglabājot vēstules tekstu, un atgriežas mapē, kura bija  atvērta pirms tam.
    </para>
 </entry>

<entry id="compose-identity">
    <title>Vēstules rakstīšana: Identitāte</title>
    <heading>Identitāte</heading>
    <para>
      No izkrītošās izvēlnes izvēlieties vieno no Personīgās informācijas sadaļā (Preferences) definētajām identitātēm, kura kalpos kā nosūtītāja atdrese.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="compose-to">
    <title>Vēstules rakstīšana: To (Kam)</title>
    <heading>"Kam"</heading>
    <para>
    Ievadiet vēstules saņēmēja(u) adresi(es). Vairāku adresātu gadījumā adrese ir jāatdala ar komatu, citi atdalītāji izraisīs kļūdu.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="compose-cc">
    <title>Vēstules rakstīšana: Cc</title>
    <heading>"Cc"</heading>
    <para>
    Ievadiet saņēmēju adreses, kuriem vēlaties nosūtīt vēstules kopijas. Vairāku adresātu gadījumā adreses ir jāatdala ar komatu, citi atdalītāji izraisīs kļūdu.
    </para>
    <para>
Vēstules kopijas parasti tiek nosūtītas adresātiem, kuri nav tiešie vēstules saņēmēji, taču kuriem ir jābūt informētiem par vēstules nosūtīšanu. Visi "To:" un "Cc:" laukos uzskaitītie saņēmēji redz vēstules adresātu uzskaitījumu.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="compose-bcc">
    <title>Vēstules rakstīšana: Bcc</title>
    <heading>"Bcc"</heading>
    <para>
    Ievadiet saņēmēju adreses, kuriem vēlaties nosūtīt slēptās vēstules kopijas. Vairāku adresātu gadījumā adreses ir jāatdala ar komatu, citi atdalītāji izraisīs kļūdu.
  </para>
   <para>
Slēptās kopijas parasti tiek sūtītas saņēmējiem, kas nav nedz tiešie, nedz netiešie saņēmēji ("To:" un "Cc:" saņēmēji), bet kuriem ir nepieciešams būt informētiem par vēstules saturu, slēpjot informāciju par saņemšanu no citiem adresātiem. Tas nozīmē, ka šo saņēmēju identitātes būs zināmas tikai vēstules nosūtītājam un slēptās kopijas saņēmējam. Piemēram, Jūs vēlaties nosūtīt vēstuli adresātam, vienlaicīgi informējot par to augstākstāvošu personu, taču nebrīdinot vēstules adresātu par šo faktu.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="compose-subject">
    <title>Vēstules rakstīšana: Temats</title>
    <heading>"Temats"</heading>
    <para>
    Norādiet vēstules tematu. Mēģiniet formulēt vēstules tematu īsu, vienkāršu un pietiekoši informatīvu. Temats ir vienkāršākais veids, lai aprakstītu vēstules saturu, kā arī - vēl svarīgāk - atvieglotu vēstuļu kārtošanu un palīdzētu sameklēt svarīgākās no tām. 
  </para>
  <para>
    Pie tam, ja pārsūtat vēstuli ar "Atbildēt" vai "Pārsūtīt", temata rinda tiek kopēta uz jauno vēstuli un tādējādi ir ļoti parocīgi izmantojama, lai noteiktu, kuras vēstules ir saistītas, veidojot sarakstes pavedienu. Vienlaikus, ja atbilde vai pārsūtījums satur jaunas idejas, Jūs varat labot temata rindu, tādējādi informējot saņēmēju(s) par sarakstes pavediena attīstību.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="compose-charset">
    <title>Vēstules rakstīšana: Kodējums</title>
    <heading>Kodējums</heading>
    <para>
    Nosaka nosūtāmās vēstules teksta kodējumu.
    </para>
    <tip>
      Tas attiecas tikai uz vēstulēm, kuras rakstāt no jauna. Atbildot uz vēstuli, (pagaidām) tiek izmantots saņemtās vēstules teksta kodējums, līdz ar ko var rasties situācija, ka atbildes vēstules saņēmējs var arī nespēt izlasīt Jūsu atbildi, ja izmantosiet, piemēram, iepraudumus kirilicā vai tml.
    </tip>
</entry>

<entry id="compose-options">
    <title>Vēstules rakstīšana: Opcijas</title>
    <heading>"Opcijas"</heading>
    <para>
    Šīs opcijas palīdz sagatavot vēstuli.
    </para>
    <para>
    Uzklikšķiniet "Pareizrakstības pārbaude" lai pārbaudītu pareizrakstību.
    </para>
    <tip>
      Ja izmantojat Mozilla Firefox, Seamonkey vao Opera pārlūkus, ieteicam izmanto tajois iebūvēto pareizrakstības pārbaudi.
    </tip>
    <para>
    Uzklikšķiniet "Pielikumi", lai pārietu uz vēstules rakstīšanas loga apakšu, kru var vēstulei pievienot pielikumus.
    </para>
    <para>
    Ja sistēma pieļauj saglabāt nosūtīto vēstuļu kopijas, aktivējiet izvēles rūtiņu "Saglabāt kopiju", lai saglabātu šīs vēstules kopiju. Vēstule tiks saglabāta vai nu noklusētajā mapē vai arī mapē, kura būs norādīta Personīgās informācijas Identitāšu sadaļā. Ja administrators ir atļāvis izvēli, Jūs varēsiet izvēlēties vēlamo mapi no izkrītošā saraksta.
  </para>
      <para>
    Saglabājiet svarīgu vēstuļu kopijas, lai vēlāk būtu iespējams atsaukt atmiņā rakstīto. Jūs varat ieslēgt šādu darbību Personīgās informācijas Identitāšu sadaļā. Jūs varat arī noteikt apkopes uzdevus, kas periodiski iztīra vai pārdēvē nosūtīto vēstuļu mapes.
  </para>
      <para>
    Neiesakām saglabāt visu nosūtīto vēstuļu kopijas, jo tādējādi Jums piešķirtā uzglabāšanas kvota var tikt izsmelta ļoti ātri, īpaši, ja sūtat vēstules ar pievienotiem failiem; Jūsu pastkastīte būs pilna un nevarēsiet saņemt jaunas vēstules.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="compose-attachments">
    <title>Vēstules rakstīšana: Pielikumu pievienošana</title>
    <heading>"Pielikumu pievienošana"</heading>
    <para>
    Jums ir iespēja pievienot vēstulei pielikumā failus, ja izmantojamā pārlūka programma uztur augšupielādi. Vienlaikus var augšupielādēt vairāk nekā 1 failu.
    </para>
    <para>Pirmais solis: ievadiet pilnu ceļu līdz pievienojamaijam failam vai arī uzklikšķiniet "Browse" pogai uz izvēlieties pievienojamo failu. Faila nosaukums un ceļš līdz tam parādās Pielikumu sadaļā. Ja Jūsu pārlūks atbalsta Javascript, Jums tiks piedāvāta papildus faila pievienošanas un vienlaicīgas augšupielādes iespēja.
    </para>
    <para>Otrais solis: Izvēlieties, vai pievienoto failu vēlaties redzēt kā pielikumu vai arī to ir jāiekļauj vēstules tekstā. Saņēmēja vēstuļu lasīšanai izmantotajai programmatūrai jābūt spējīgai apstrādāt ietvertā faila tipu, citādi šī daļa tiks attēlota kā pielikums.
    </para>
    <para>
    Ja vien nevēlaties mainīt pielikumu aprakstu vai arī norādīt, ka pielikumu ir jāietver tekstā, pielikumu pievienošanu var uzskatīt par pabeigtu. Pielikumi tisk augšupielādi, kad nospiedīsiet pogu Sūtīt. Ja vēlaties mainit aprakstu, vai pielikuma izvietojumu vēstulē, varat nospiest pogu "Apstiprināt" lai augšupielādētu pielikumus uzreiz un saglabātu citas izmaiņas pievienotajos pielikumos.
    </para>

    <tip>
    Ņemiet vērā, ka lielu failu vai lēna Internet pieslēguma gadījumā pielikumu augšupielāde un pievienošana vēstulei var patērēt zināmu laiku. Esit pacietīgi un neklikšķiņiet uz citām saitēm un pogām, kamēr notiek faila (-u) augšupielāde.
    </tip>
</entry>

<entry id="compose-current-attachments">
    <title>Vēstules rakstīšana: Pievienotie pielikumi</title>
    <heading>Pievienotie pielikumi</heading>
    <para>
    Šajā sadaļā tiek parādīti vēstulei jau pievienotie faili.
    </para>
    <heading>Dzēst pievienoto(s) failu(s)</heading>
    <para>
    Lai dzēstu pievienoto(s) failu(s):
    </para>
    <para>
    Pirmais: Ieķesējiet rūtiņu blakus dzēšamā faila nosaukumam.
    </para>
    <para>
    Otrais:  Lai uzreiz redzētu izmaiņas, uzklikšķiniet pogu "Apstiprināt" virs pievienoto pielikumu sekcijas vai arī izmaiņas tiks izdarītas automātiski nosūtot vēstuli.
    </para>
    <heading>Mainīt pielikuma izvietojumu</heading>
    <para>
    Lai mainītu pielikumu izvietojumu:
    </para>
    <para>
    Pirmais: Izmainiet katra pielikuma izvietojumu - vai nu uz "iekļauts" vai "pielikums" - pēc vajadzības.
    </para>
    <para>
    Otrais:  Lai uzreiz redzētu izmaiņas, uzklikšķiniet pogu "Apstiprināt" virs pievienoto pielikumu sekcijas vai arī izmaiņas tiks izdarītas automātiski nosūtot vēstuli.
    </para>
    <heading>Mainīt pielikuma aprakstu</heading>
    <para>
    Lai manītu pielikuma aprakstu (tekstu, ko kā pielikuma aprakstu redzēs saņemējs):
    </para>
    <para>
    Pirmais: Ievadiet aprakstu Apraksta laukā.
    </para>
    <para>
    Otrais:  Lai uzreiz redzētu izmaiņas, uzklikšķiniet pogu "Apstiprināt" virs pievienoto pielikumu sekcijas vai arī izmaiņas tiks izdarītas automātiski nosūtot vēstuli.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="compose-priority">
    <title>Vēstules rakstīšana: Prioritāte</title>
    <heading>Prioritāte</heading>
    <para>
    Uzstāda Jūsu nosūtāmās vēstules "X-Priority" galveni. "X-Priority" iezīme ir sava veida standarts, par ko ir vienojušies Netscape, Mozilla, Opera un  Outlook pasta klienti. Citi klienti, kas neuztur šādas iezīmes lietošanu, to vienkārši ignorēs.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="compose-save-attachments">
    <title>Vēstules rakstīšana: Saglabāt pielikumu(s)</title>
    <para>
    Nosaka, vai Jūsu sastādītās vēstules pielikumi tiks saglabāti kopā ar vēstuli nosūtīto vēstuļu mapē. "Jā" nozīmē pielikumu saglabāšanu, "Nē" - pielikumi tiks aizvākti no vēstules pēc tās nosūtīšanas visiem saņēmējiem. Izvēloties "Nē" un nesaglabājot potenciāli liela izmēra pielikums Jūs palīdzēsiet taupīgi izmantot brīvo vietu uz servera diskiem.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="compose-link-attachments">
    <title>Vēstules rakstīšana: Piesaistīt pielikumu(s)</title>
    <para>
    Nosaka, vai Jūs vēstules pielikumi tiks nosūtīti kā vēstules sastāvdaļa vai arī pielikumi tiks saglabāti uz lokālā servera. Piesaistīto pielikumu gadījumā saņēmējs(-i) vēstulē saņems lejupielādes saiti un varēs lejupielādēt pielikumus patstāvīgi. Pielikumu piesaiste priekšrocība - tā palīdz būtiski samazināt izejošo sūtījumu apjomu. Piesaistes trūkums - nav iespējams garantēt, ka piesaistītais pielikums būs pieejams vienmēr, jo pielikuma dati tiek nošķirti no saņemtās vestules.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="folder-options">
    <title>Mapes: Mapju vadība</title>
    <para>
      Mapes var izvēlēties atķeksējot kreisajā malā esošās rūtiņas. Pēc izvēles pabeigšanas, izvēlieties darbību no izklītošās Darbību izvēlnes.
    </para>
    <heading>Izveidot</heading>
    <para>
      Ja iespējams, izveidot jaunu mapi. Lai izveidotu mapi pamatlīmenī, izvēlieties 'Izveidot' neatzīmējot nevienu mapi kreisajā slejā. Lai izveidotu apakšmapi jau eksistējošā mapē, atzīmējiet to kreisajā slejā pirms 'Izveidot' izvēles.
    </para>
    <heading>Pārdevēt</heading>
    <para>
      Pārdēvē mapi. Lai pārdēvētu, atzīmējiet mapes kreisajā slejā un izvēlieties 'Pārdēvēt'. Pārdēvējot vienlaikus tiek pārdēvētas arī visas apakšmapes.
    </para>
    <heading>Dzēst</heading>
    <para>
      Dzēs mapi un visas tajā atrodošās vēstules. Lai dzēstu, atzīmējiet dzēšamās mapes kreisajā slejā un izvēlieties 'Dzēst'. Ja dzēšat mapi ar apakšmapēm, tās netiks automātiski izdzēstas. Lai izdzēstu apakšmapes, tās ir jāatzīmē kreisajā slejā un jāizvēlas 'Dzēst'.
    </para>
    <heading>Iztukšot</heading>
    <para>
      Lai dzēstu visas mapē atrodošās vēstules saglabājot pašu mapi, kreisajā slejā atzīmējiet iztukšojamās mapes un izvēlieties 'Iztukšot'.
    </para>
    <heading>Iztīrīt</heading>
    <para>
      Lai dzēstu visas mapē atrodošās vēstules saglabājot pašu mapi, kreisajā slejā atzīmējiet iztukšojamās mapes un izvēlieties 'Iztīrīt'. Šāda darbība parādās tikai tad, ja neizmantojat Atkritumu mapi.
    </para>
    <heading>Parakstīties/Atrakstīties</heading>
    <para>
      Atzīmē mapi kā parakstītu vai neparakstītu. Ja mape ir parakstīta, tā parādīsies visos izkrītošajos mapju sarakstos. Šī iespēja parādās tikai lietojot IMAP mapju parakstīšanos.
    </para>
    <para>
      Lai parakstītos, atzīmējiet vajadzīgās mapes kreisajā slejā un izvēlieties 'Parakstīties'. Lai atrakstītos, atzīmējiet vajadzīgās mapes kreisajā slejā un izvēlieties 'Atrakstīties'.
    </para>
    <heading>Pārbaudīt jaunpienākušo pastu/Nepārbaudīt jaunpienākušo pastu</heading>
    <para>
      Atzīmē pārbaudāmo mapi Mapju navigatorā un sānjoslā (ja ieslēgta).
    </para>
    <para>
      Lai uzstādītu šo karogu, atzīmējiet vajadzīgās mapes kreisajā slejā un izvēlieties 'Pārbaudīt jaunpienākušo pastu'. Lai atceltu šo karogu, atzīmējiet vajadzīgās mapes kreisajā slejā un izvēlieties 'Nepārbaudīt jaunpienākušo pastu'. 
    </para>
    <heading>Atzīmēt visas vēstules kā redzētas/neredzētas</heading>
    <para>
       Lai atzīmētu visas vēstules mapē kā redzētas, atzīmējit vajadzīgās mapes kreisajā slejā in izvēlieties 'Atzīmēt visas vēstules kā redzētas'. Lai atzīmētu visas vēstules mapē kā neredzētas, atzīmējit vajadzīgās mapes kreisajā slejā in izvēlieties 'Atzīmēt visas vēstules kā neredzētas'.
    </para>
    <heading>Lejuplādēt</heading>
    <para>
      Lai lejupielādētu visas vēstules vienā failā (mbox formātā), kresajā slejā atzīmējit vajadzīgo mapi un  izvēlieties 'Lejuplādēt'. Lai lejuplādētu vēstules saspiestā veidā, izvēlieties 'Lejuplādēt [zip. formāts]'.
    </para>
    <heading>Importēt vēstules</heading>
    <para>
      Ar šo darbību ir iepsējams importēt mbox formāta vai .eml failus Jūsu izvēlētajā mapē. Izvēlieties mērķa mapi un izvēlieties 'Importēt'. Jums tiks piedāvāts norādīt importējamo mbox vai .eml failu.
    </para>
    <heading>Atsvaidzināt mapju koku</heading>
    <para>
      Atskaidzina mapju koka grafisko attēlojumu pieprasot informāciju no pasta servera. Šī nav ikdienišķa darbība, ja vien vienlaicīgi nepieslēdzaties pasta serverim ar citu klientu un šis klients izdara izmaiņas mapju struktūrā.
    </para>
    <heading>Rādīt/slēpt neparakstītās</heading>
    <para>
      Ja izmantojat IMAP mapju parakstīšanos/atrakstīšanos, parāda vai paslēpj mapes. Lai parakstītos/atrakstītos uz mapi, atzīmējiet to kreisajā slejā  un izvēlieties 'Pakstīties/Atrakstīes' darbību.
    </para>
    <heading>Izvērst visu</heading>
    <para>
    Izvērst visu mapju koku.
    </para>
    <heading>Savērst visu</heading>
    <para>
    Savērst visu mapju koku.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="filters">
    <title>Filtri: Pielietot</title>
    <heading>Pielieto filtru likumus</heading>
    <para>
    Uzklikšķiniet uz "Pielietot filtrus' ikonas blakus INBOX vārdam pastkastes skatā, lai filtrtētu vēstules atbilstoši definētajiem filtru likumiem.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="filter-edit-rules">
    <title>Filtri: Labot filtru likumus</title>
    <heading>Labot filtru likumus</heading>
    <para>
    Uzklikšķiniet "Labot filtru likumus" lai pievienotu, labotu vai dzēstu definētos filtru likumus.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="filter-edit-blacklist">
    <title>Filtri: Labot melno sarakstu</title>
    <heading>Labot melno sarakstu</heading>
    <para>
    Uzklikšķiniet "Labot melno sarakstu" lai pievienotu, labotu vai dzēstu e-pasta adreses, no kurām vēstules nevēlaties saņemt NEKAD.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="filter-edit-whitelist">
    <title>Filtri: Labot balto sarakstu</title>
    <heading>Labot balto sarakstu</heading>
    <para>
    Uzklikšķiniet "Labot balto sarakstu" lai pievienotu, labotu vai dzēstu e-pasta adreses, no kurām vēstules vēlaties saņemt VIENMĒR.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="filter-on-login">
    <title>Filtri: Filtrēt pieslēdzoties</title>
    <heading>Pielietot filtrēšanas likumus pieslēdzoties?</heading>
    <para>
      Izvēlieties šo iestatījumu, ja vēlaties pielietot filtrēšanas likumus pieslēdzoties IMP.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="filter-on-display">
    <title>Filtri: Filtrēt atsvaidzinot</title>
    <heading>Pielieto filtrēšanas likumus vienmēr, kad tiek atvērts INBOX?</heading>
    <para>
    Izvēlieties šo iestatījumu, ja vēlaties pielietot filtrēšanas likumus vienmēr, kad tiek atvērts INBOX.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="filter-any-mailbox">
    <title>Filtri: Filtrēt ikvienu pastkasti</title>
    <heading>Pielietot filtrēšanas likumus izvienai pastkastei?</heading>
    <para>
      
    Check this option if you want to be allowed to apply filter rules to any mailbox. Normally, filtering rules are only applied to new mail that is delivered to your INBOX. If this option is checked, an icon will appear on all mailbox pagges that will allow you to apply filter rules to the messages in the current mailbox. NOTE: Filtering in mailboxes other than INBOX may produce strange (e.g. the filter may cause a copy of messages to be delivered to the same mailbox) and/or undesired results (e.g. it may cause messages to be moved/deleted if new filtering rules have been implemented since the message has been delivered to the current mailbox).
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="pgp-compose-attach-pubkey" state="new">
    <title>PGP: Attach Public Key</title>
    <heading>Attach Public Key</heading>
    <para>
    If selected then a copy of your PGP public key, if it exists, will be attached to the outgoing message. You can set the default behavior via the PGP Preferences screen.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="pgp-option-scan-body" state="new">
    <title>PGP: Scan Text Bodies</title>
    <heading>Scan Text Bodies</heading>
    <para>
    If selected then IMP will scan the body of all text messages for PGP data, and display the results if any data is found. Note that this may slow down the system as every text message must be scanned in its entirety for PGP data.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="pgp-option-reply-pubkey" state="new">
    <title>PGP: Validate PGP Public Keys When Replying</title>
    <heading>Validate PGP Public Keys When Replying</heading>
    <para>
    If set, and PGP encryption is used by default for composing messages, IMP will verify that it can access all recipients' public keys when the reply is first created. This has the disadvantage that it may cause a delay in opening the reply window. However, it has the advantage of informing you immediately if you will be able to correctly send the encrypted message to all recipients immediately.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="compose-options-encrypt" state="new">
    <title>Message Composition: Encryption Options</title>
    <heading>No Encryption</heading>
    <para>
    Send the message with no encryption (cleartext).
    </para>
    <heading>PGP Encrypt Message</heading>
    <para>
    This option will encrypt the current message, using PGP and the recipients personal public key, and then send it. You MUST have the public key of the recipient stored in your addressbook or else this option will fail. If you have the public key for the recipient in your addressbook and are still receiving errors, verify that the e-mail address in the recipient field matches the e-mail address where the public key is stored. The encrypted data will be attached to the outgoing message.
    </para>
    <heading>PGP Sign Message</heading>
    <para>
    This option will digitally sign the current message using PGP and your personal private key. If you have not already entered the passphrase for your private key during this session you will be prompted for it. The recipient must have a copy of your public key to digitally verify your signature.
    </para>
    <heading>PGP Sign/Encrypt Message</heading>
    <para>
    This option will first digitally sign your message and then will encrypt the resulting output. See the "PGP Encrypt Message" and "PGP Sign Message" entries for further information.
    </para>
    <heading>PGP Encrypt Message with passphrase</heading>
    <para>
    This option will encrypt the current message, using PGP and a passphrase, and then send it. You will be prompted for the passphrase that should be used for the encryption. Give the passphrase to the recipient through a secure channel e.g. personally, by phone, etc. The encrypted data will be attached to the outgoing message.
    </para>
    <heading>PGP Sign/Encrypt Message with passphrase</heading>
    <para>
    This option will first digitally sign your message and then will encrypt the resulting output with a passphrase. See the "PGP Encrypt Message with passphrase" and "PGP Sign Message" entries for further information.
    </para>
    <heading>S/MIME Encrypt Message</heading>
    <para>
    This option will encrypt the current message, using S/MIME and the recipients certificate, and then send it. You MUST have the certificate of the recipient stored in your addressbook or else this option will fail. If you have the certificate for the recipient in your addressbook and are still receiving errors, verify that the e-mail address in the recipient field matches the e-mail address where the certificate is stored. The encrypted data will be attached to the outgoing message.
    </para>
    <heading>S/MIME Sign Message</heading>
    <para>
    This option will digitally sign the current message using S/MIME and your certificate. If you have not already entered the passphrase for your certificate during this session you will be prompted for it.
    </para>
    <heading>S/MIME Sign/Encrypt Message</heading>
    <para>
    This option will first digitally sign your message and then will encrypt the resulting output. See the "S/MIME Encrypt Message" and "S/MIME Sign Message" entries for further information.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="pgp-overview" state="new">
    <title>PGP: Overview</title>
    <heading>What is PGP?</heading>
    <para>
    PGP is a tool for secure communication and data storage, especially for use with e-mail. It can be used to encrypt data and to create digital signatures. IMP uses GnuPG (GNU Privacy Guard) to provide this functionality.
    </para>
    <heading>Enable PGP functionality?</heading>
    <para>
    If this option is selected, you will be able to create/view your personal PGP keys, add/delete public keys from other individuals, read encrypted mail, verify digitally signed mail, and encrypt/sign your outgoing mail.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="pgp-option-attach-pubkey" state="new">
    <title>PGP: Options - Attach Public Key</title>
    <heading>Options - Attach Public Key</heading>
    <para>
    If selected then a copy of your PGP public key, if it exists, will by default be attached to all outgoing messages.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="pgp-manage-pubkey" state="new">
    <title>PGP: Manage Public Keys</title>
    <heading>Overview</heading>
    <para>
    This screen lists all of the current users in your addressbook that have PGP public keys. These users are the ONLY users that you can either 1) send an encrypted message to -OR- 2) verify a digital signature.
    </para>
    <heading>View</heading>
    <para>
    Opens a window to view the PGP public key.
    </para>
    <heading>Details</heading>
    <para>
    Displays some details about the PGP public key.
    </para>
    <heading>Delete</heading>
    <para>
    Deletes the public key from your addressbook.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="pgp-import-pubkey" state="new">
    <title>PGP: Manage Public Keys - Import</title>
    <heading>Import Public Keys</heading>
    <para>
    This button will open a window where you can manually import a PGP public key. The key can either be pasted into a textfield or, if the key resides in a file on your local computer, you can import it. If the key is valid it will be inserted into your addressbook and the window will close; if not valid, an error message will be returned explaining why.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="pgp-overview-personalkey" state="new">
    <title>PGP: Manage Personal Keys</title>
    <heading>Overview</heading>
    <para>
    If you want to digitally sign messages or enable others to send you encrypted messages, you must have your own personal public/private PGP keypair.
    </para>
    <heading>Your Public Key</heading>
    <para>
    Your public key should be made available to any person that you want to be able to send you encrypted messages that only YOU can decrypt (using your private key). Additionally, your public key needs to be made available to anybody you send a digitally signed message to - the public key is required to verify the digital signature.
    </para>
    <heading>Your Private Key</heading>
    <para>
    Your private key is necessary to decrypt any message encrypted using your public key. Additionally, your private key is needed if you want to digitally sign a message. Your private key will be protected via a passphrase created when the keys are generated. Thus, to perform any activity that requires your private key, IMP will prompt you for your passphrase. You only need to insert your passphrase once per session - IMP will store your passphrase until you logout (So be sure to logout!).
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="pgp-personalkey-public" state="new">
    <title>PGP: Manage Personal Keys - Public Key</title>
    <heading>View</heading>
    <para>
    Opens a window to view the PGP public key.
    </para>
    <heading>Details</heading>
    <para>
    Displays some details about the PGP public key.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="pgp-personalkey-private" state="new">
    <title>PGP: Manage Personal Keys - Private Key</title>
    <heading>Enter Passphrase</heading>
    <para>
    Opens the passphrase dialog window. The passphrase entered, if correct, will be stored by IMP until your session ends.
    </para>
    <heading>Unload Passphrase</heading>
    <para>
    Removes the stored passphrase from IMP - any additional usage of the private key will require you to reenter the passphease.
    </para>
    <heading>View</heading>
    <para>
    Opens a window to view the PGP private key. DO NOT SEND THIS KEY TO ANYONE - this option is strictly so that you can export your IMP personal private key for use in another program.
    </para>
    <heading>Details</heading>
    <para>
    Displays some details about the PGP private key.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="pgp-personalkey-delete" state="new">
    <title>PGP: Manage Personal Keys - Delete</title>
    <heading>Delete Personal Keys</heading>
    <para>
    This button will delete your personal public/private keypair from IMP's preferences.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="pgp-personalkey-create-name" state="new">
    <title>PGP: Create Personal Key - Name</title>
    <heading>Name</heading>
    <para>
    The name you want embedded in your personal keys. A required field.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="pgp-personalkey-create-comment" state="new">
    <title>PGP: Create Personal Key - Comment</title>
    <heading>Comment</heading>
    <para>
    A comment string you want embedded in your personal keys. An optional field.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="pgp-personalkey-create-email" state="new">
    <title>PGP: Create Personal Key - E-mail Address</title>
    <heading>E-mail Address</heading>
    <para>
    The e-mail address you want associated with your personal keys. A required field.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="pgp-personalkey-create-keylength" state="new">
    <title>PGP: Create Personal Key - Keylength</title>
    <heading>Keylength</heading>
    <para>
    The keylength, in bit, of your generated key. The greater the value, the greater the protection (and also greater generation time and encryption time). 1024 bit is the default - this value provides excellent protection.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="pgp-personalkey-create-passphrase" state="new">
    <title>PGP: Create Personal Key - Passphrase</title>
    <heading>Passphrase</heading>
    <para>
    The passphrase used to protect/encrypt your personal private key. This should be AT LEAST 6 characters, should NOT be the same as your login password, should NOT be based on a dictionary word, and should include both numbers and letters. You must enter this passphrase twice for verification purposes. A required field.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="pgp-personalkey-create-actions" state="new">
    <title>PGP: Create Personal Key - Actions</title>
    <heading>Create Keys</heading>
    <para>
    Create and store your personal public/private keypair.
    </para>
    <heading>Import Keypair</heading>
    <para>
    Import a personal/private keypair. This button opens a window where you can manually import your existing PGP personal public/private keypair. The keys can either be pasted into a textfield or, if the keys reside in a file on your local computer, you can import them. If the keys are valid they will be inserted into your preferences and the window will close; if not valid, an error message will be returned explaining why.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="smime-overview" state="new">
    <title>S/MIME: Overview</title>
    <heading>What is S/MIME?</heading>
    <para>
    S/MIME is a private/public key pair system which provides digital signatures, message privacy, and tamper detection in a open, interoperable way. S/MIME can provide message privacy by encrypting messages that only the sender and the intended recipients can decode. It allows you to identify the sender of a message via a digital signature. Together, this encryption and digital signing help provide tamper detection, allowing recipients to determine whether a message was altered after it was sent.
    </para>
    <heading>Enable S/MIME functionality?</heading>
    <para>
    If this option is selected, you will be able to import your personal S/MIME keys, read encrypted mail, verify digitally signed mail, and encrypt/sign your outgoing mail.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="smime-overview-personalkey" state="new">
    <title>S/MIME: Personal Keys</title>
    <heading>Overview</heading>
    <para>
    If you want to digitally sign or encrypt messages you must have your own personal public/private S/MIME keypair.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="smime-import-personal-certs" state="new">
    <title>S/MIME: Import Personal Certificates</title>
    <heading>Import Personal Certificates</heading>
    <para>
    Import personal certificates from a PKCS #12 format file. PKCS #12 files is the file usually generated when exporting a key from a browser (e.g. Internet Explorer, Firefox) or from a certificate store maintained by an Operating System (e.g. Windows XP). If the keys are valid they will be inserted into your preferences and the window will close; if not valid, an error message will be returned explaining why.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="smime-delete-personal-certs" state="new">
    <title>S/MIME: Delete Personal Certificates</title>
    <heading>Delete Personal Certificates</heading>
    <para>
    Delete your personal certificates from your preferences.  You will no longer be able to sign S/MIME messages or view any S/MIME encrypted messages addressed to you.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="smime-manage-pubkey" state="new">
    <title>S/MIME: Manage Public Keys</title>
    <heading>S/MIME: Manage Public Keys</heading>
    <para>
    Manage your S/MIME public key list.
    </para>
    <heading>View</heading>
    <para>
    View the raw text of the public key.
    </para>
    <heading>Details</heading>
    <para>
    View technical details of the public key.
    </para>
    <heading>Delete</heading>
    <para>
    Deletes the selected public key from storage.  Deleting a public key for a user will prevent your from encrypting a message to that user.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="printing" state="new">
    <title>Printing</title>
    <heading>Print a message</heading>
    <para>
    To print a message you are viewing, click on the "Print" link at either the top or bottom of the message. The message will open in a new window formated for printing. Depending on your web browser and operating system, the print dialog box may open for you. If it does not open, then pull down the web browser's "File" menu and choose "Print" to open the print dialog box.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="sorting" state="new">
    <title>Sorting and Threading</title>
    <heading>Sorting Entries</heading>
    <para>
    When viewing a list of messages, you can sort the messages by any column by clicking on the appropriate column heading. To switch columns between ascending and descending order, click on the arrow icon in the column heading.
    </para>
    <heading>Threading</heading>
    <para>
    To group messages by threads (subject), so each message is grouped with all its replies, click the [Thread] link in the subject column heading. To return to normal subject sorting, click on the [Subject] link in the subject column heading.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="prefs-rename_sentmail_monthly" state="new">
    <title>Preferences: Rename Sent Mail Folder Monthly</title>
    <para>
    Turn this preference on if you would like to rename your sent mail folder at the beginning of every month. The folder will be renamed (to a name that contains the month and year) and a new sent mail folder will be created.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="prefs-delete_sentmail_monthly_keep" state="new">
    <title>Preferences: Delete Sent Mail Folder Monthly</title>
    <para>
    This option will purge old sent mail folders after a given number of months.  Any folders older than this value will be deleted.  This may be useful if you have a quota, for example.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="prefs-purge_sentmail_interval" state="new">
    <title>Preferences: Purge Sent Mail</title>
    <para>
    How often should your sent mail folder(s) be purged?
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="prefs-purge_sentmail_keep" state="new">
    <title>Preferences: Purge Sent Mail Keep</title>
    <para>
    If you are purging your sent mail folder(s), message older than how many days should be purged?
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="prefs-delete_attachments_monthly_keep" state="new">
    <title>Preferences: Delete Linked Attachments Monthly</title>
    <para>
    If your local account is configured to allow sending linked attachments in outgoing compose messages, this option will purge old linked attachments after a given number of months.  Any attachments older than this value will be deleted.  This may be useful if you have a quota, for example.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="prefs-purge_trash_interval" state="new">
    <title>Preferences: Maintenance: Purge Trash</title>
    <para>
    How often should your trash folder be purged?
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="prefs-purge_trash_keep" state="new">
    <title>Preferences: Maintenance: Purge Trash Keep</title>
    <para>
    If you are purging your trash folder, message older than how many days should be purged?
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="prefs-purge_spam_interval" state="new">
    <title>Preferences: Maintenance: Purge Spam</title>
    <para>
    How often should your spam folder be purged?
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="prefs-purge_spam_keep" state="new">
    <title>Preferences: Maintenance: Purge Spam Keep</title>
    <para>
    If you are purging your spam folder, message older than how many days should be purged?
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="prefs-attrib_text" state="new">
     <title>Preferences: Message Composition: Attribution Text</title>
     <para>
     Here you can enter the phrase that you wish to appear before any quoted text in a reply that you send.
     </para>
     <para>
     You can include one or more special placeholders to insert information about the message to which you are replying. Placeholders consist of a '%' followed by a single letter. The following placeholders are available:
     </para>

     <para> %f : The sender's name and email address</para>
     <para> %a : The sender's email address</para>
     <para> %p : The sender's name</para>
     <para> %r : The full RFC 2822 style date and time zone</para>
     <para> %d : The date as www, dd mmm YYYY</para>
     <para> %x : The date in the locale's default</para>
     <para> %c : The date and time in the locale's default</para>
     <para> %m : The Message-ID</para>
     <para> %s : The subject</para>
     <para> %n : A new line</para>
     <para> %% : The '%' character</para>

</entry>

<entry id="prefs-default_msg_charset" state="new">
    <title>Preferences: Default Message Character Set</title>
    <para>
    Define the default character set to use for text message parts that do not contain explicit character set information. Per RFC 2045, messages without a character set parameter are displayed using the 'US-ASCII' character set. However, certain badly broken mailers may send out text messages in other character sets without setting the proper parameters in the message header. Set this parameter to the default character set string to use locally. Select "Default" to use the MIME defaults.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="prefs-request_mdn" state="new">
    <title>Preferences: Request Read Receipts</title>
    <para>
    "Request a Read Receipt" sends a read receipt request (also known as a Message Dispositon Notification) to the recipients of a composed message to notify you when this message is opened by the recipients. Not all clients support / honor this.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="prefs-send_mdn" state="new">
    <title>Preferences: Send Read Receipt</title>
    <para>
    "Send a Read Receipt" sends a read receipt (also known as a Message Disposition Notification) when you view a message in which the user has requested that they receive notification that you have read the message. By default, you will be prompted to send the notification.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="prefs-delete_spam_after_report" state="new">
    <title>Preferences: Delete Spam After Reporting</title>
    <para>
    You may elect to do one of three items after reporting a message as spam.
    </para>
    <para>
    First, you can decide to do nothing - the message will be reported as spam but will otherwise remain unchanged in your mailbox.
    </para>
    <para>
    Second, if reporting a message as spam, you can instead have the message be immediately deleted.
    </para>
    <para>
    Third, after reporting a message as spam the message will be deleted from the current mailbox and moved to your spam folder.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="prefs-move_ham_after_report" state="new">
    <title>Preferences: Move Spam After Reporting As Innocent</title>
    <para>
    You may elect to do one of two items after reporting a message previously maked as spam as innocent.
    </para>
    <para>
    First, you can decide to do nothing - the message will be reported as innocent but will otherwise remain unchanged in your mailbox.
    </para>
    <para>
    Second, if reporting a message as innocent the message will be deleted from the current mailbox and moved to your Inbox.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="prefs-image_replacement" state="new">
    <title>Preferences: Image Replacement</title>
    <para>
    For messages displayed inline, should all image tags be blocked until you specifically decide to view those images? Note that, if viewing as an attachment, the images will always be displayed.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="prefs-image_addrbook" state="new">
    <title>Preferences: Image Replacement/Addressbook Show</title>
    <para>
    If blocking images for inline messages, should they be displayed automatically if the sender appears in your addressbook?
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="prefs-mailbox_start" state="new">
    <title>Preferences: Mailbox Start Page</title>
    <para>
    Determines which page in the mailbox view will be displayed when you access a mailbox for the first time.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="prefs-save_attachments" state="new">
    <title>Preferences: Save Attachments on Sent Messages</title>
    <para>
    If saving a composed message in a sent mail folder, determine if all attachment data is saved. The following options are available:
    </para>

    <para>* "Always save attachments" - NEVER prompt to save attachments in compose screen; the attachments are ALWAYS saved with the message.</para>
     <para>* "Prompt every time an attachment is sent; default to YES" - ALWAYS prompt to save attachments in the compose screen; the default is to save attachments.</para>
     <para>* "Prompt every time an attachment is sent; default to NO" - ALWAYS prompt to save attachments in the compose screen; the default is to not save attachments.</para>
     <para>* "Never save attachments" - NEVER prompt to save attachments in compose screen; the attachments are NEVER saved with the message.</para>
</entry>

<entry id="virtual_inbox" state="new">
    <title>Folders: Virtual Inbox</title>
    <para>
    Virtual Inbox is a saved search that does away with the need to search every mailbox for messages marked as new.  Instead, all currently subscribed mailboxes are searched for new messages and the results are displayed in a single mailbox.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="virtual_trash" state="new">
    <title>Folders: Virtual Trash</title>
    <para>
    Virtual Trash is a saved search that does away with the need for a separate Trash folder.  Instead of moving messages to a centralized trash folder, messages are simply marked as deleted in the current folder they live in.  When 'show deleted messages' is turned off, this results in these messages not appearing in a mailbox view.  When a user clicks on Virtual Trash, *all* mailboxes are searched for messages that are flagged deleted and these messages are displayed in a single mailbox.
    </para>
</entry>

</help>
