<?xml version="1.0" ?>
<help>

<entry id="overview">
  <title>Overview</title>
  <heading>Introduction</heading>

  <para>
    This application provides image manipulation, storage, and display
    capabilities for you to have online photo albums and
    galleries. You can resize, rotate, and otherwise alter your
    images, organize them, name them, and give them descriptions.
  </para>
</entry>

<entry id="upload">
  <title>Uploading Images: Overview</title>

  <para>
    You can upload most common kinds of images. If there is a problem
    with an uploaded file, you will be notified, so when in doubt,
    give it a try. You also have two options if you have a lot of
    images to upload at once. You can upload a ZIP file of all of the
    images, and they will all be processed at once. Or, if you are
    using Windows XP, you can use the <ref ENTRY="xppublish"
    MODULE="ansel">XP Publishing Wizard</ref>.
  </para>
</entry>

<entry id="xppublish">
  <title>Uploading Images: Publish from Windows XP</title>
  <heading>Using Windows XP's Publish to the Web feature</heading>

  <para>
    Windows XP comes with a nice feature that allows you to publish
    content from your desktop directly to a web service.
  </para>

  <para><b>1. Setting it up</b></para>

  <para>
    Download the <href url="xppublish.php" app="ansel">XP
    Configuration file</href>. Save it to your desktop, and make sure
    that the file extension is .reg. If it is not, rename the file,
    and if Windows asks you to confirm changing the type of the file,
    say yes.
  </para>

  <para>
    Double-click on install-registry.reg. You will be asked whether or
    not you want to import these values into your registry. Click
    &quot;OK&quot;. You will be told that the values were imported
    successfully; click &quot;OK&quot; again. You are now ready to
    upload files!
  </para>

  <para><b>2. Uploading</b></para>

  <para>
    Open Windows Explorer and browse to the folder that you want to
    upload, or that contains the file(s) that you'd like to upload.
    Make sure that you can see &quot;File and Folder Tasks&quot; on
    the left of your Explorer window. You should see an option to
    &quot;Publish this folder to the Web&quot; or, if you have a
    specific file selected, &quot;Publish this file to the Web&quot;.
    Click this link and then follow the instructions to select which
    files you want to upload (you will get to select anything in the
    folder during the process), log in, select a gallery or create a
    new one, and publish the image(s).
  </para>
</entry>

</help>
