<?xml version="1.0"?>
<help>

  <entry id="Overview">
    <title>Chora Overview</title>
    <para>
      Chora is a tool for viewing code repositories that are managed using
      source control systems. It provides a directory (file) view, a log
      history view, difference views between versions, a visual branch view,
      and an annotated view.
    </para>
  </entry>

  <entry id="chora-button">
    <title>Menu Buttons: Browse</title>
    <para>
      The Browse button takes you back to the main Chora files view for the
      default repository.
    </para>
  </entry>

  <entry id="prefs-button">
    <title>Menu Buttons: Preferences</title>
    <para>
      The Preferences button lets you set some personal preferences to control the
      way Chora behaves.
    </para>
  </entry>

  <entry id="help-button">
    <title>Menu Buttons: Help</title>
    <para>
      The Help button brings up this help display.
    </para>
  </entry>

  <entry id="view-checkout">
    <title>Checkout View</title>
    <para>
      The Checkout View shows a file contents at a revision point, along with
      the log entry for that revision.
    </para>
  </entry>

  <entry id="view-annotate">
    <title>Annotate View</title>
    <para>
      The Annotated View shows a file annotated with which authors are
      responsible for which portions of a file's contents (and is hence often
      called the "blame" view).
    </para>
  </entry>

  <entry id="view-branch">
    <title>Branch View</title>
    <para>
      The Branch View shows a file's version history, layed out by
      branches. This allows you to visually see where branch points were
      created in the tree.
    </para>
  </entry>

  <entry id="view-log">
    <title>Log View</title>
    <para>
      The Log View shows a file's history via the checkin log messages. This
      allows you to see a history of changes from the point of view log
      messages entered at checkin time.
    </para>
  </entry>

  <entry id="view-diff">
    <title>Differences View</title>
    <para>
      The Differences View shows the differences between two different
      revisions of a file. This allows you to easily see how a file has
      changed.  You can view the differences in various formats, including
      among others a color coded side by side listing of the two revisions, or
      in terms of ed editor commands.
    </para>
  </entry>

  <entry id="show-deleted-files">
    <title>Show/Hide Deleted Files</title>
    <para>
      You can choose to either view deleted files (from the Attic) or to not
      show (hide) deleted files in the file view.  If you choose to show
      deleted files, they will show up dimmed and with a <i>trash can</i>
      icon.
    </para>
    <para>
      The default is not to show deleted files.
    </para>
  </entry>

</help>
