<?xml version='1.0'?>
<help>

<entry id="tag_level">
    <title>General Options: Tag Level</title>
    <heading>Tag Level</heading>
    <para>
        Specify the minimum score required to add a <b>X-Spam-Status:</b>
        header to the message. This header does not necessarily means that
        the message is spam, but will display the score this message received
        and which tests it failed.
    </para>
    <para>
        The lower the score, the more aggressive tagging becomes. For example,
        a score of 2.0 will add the header to messages of 2.0 and above, and
        is a very aggressive setting.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="hit_level">
    <title>General Options: Hit Level</title>
    <heading>Hit Level</heading>
    <para>
        Specify the minimum score required to add a <b>X-Spam-Flag: YES</b>
        header for messages identified as SPAM. This header can be used for
        filtering rule creation.
    </para>
    <para>
        The lower the Hit Level, the more aggressive the filter will be when
        marking messages as spam. For example, a Hit Level of 2.0 will mark
        any message with a score of 2.0 and higher as spam. This is a very
        aggressive setting. The Hit Level should generally be higher than the
        <i>Tag Level</i> setting (if enabled). A Hit Level of 5.0 is the
        default setting.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="kill_level">
    <title>General Options: Kill Level</title>
    <heading>Kill Level</heading>
    <para>
        Specify the minimum score required to take evasive action against
        identified SPAM messages. Actions are system-specific and may include
        filtering into another mailbox or silently discarding.
    </para>
    <para>
        The lower the score, the more aggressive tagging becomes.  For example,
        a score of 2.0 will add the header to messages of 2.0 and above, and
        is a very aggressive setting. This setting should generally be equal
        to or lower than the <i>Hit Level</i> setting (if enabled).
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="subject_tag">
    <title>General Options: Subject Tag</title>
    <heading>Subject Tag</heading>
    <para>
        Text prepended to the Subject: line of messages that are considered
        SPAM, if <i>Rewrite Subject</i> setting is turned on.
    </para>
    <para>
        If the scanning engine supports it, the word <b>_HITS_</b> in the tag
        will be replaced with the calculated score for this message and the
        word <b>_REQD_</b> will be replaced with the threshold required, which
        is value of the <i>Hit Level</i> setting.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="rewrite_sub">
    <title>General Options: Rewrite Subject</title>
    <heading>Rewrite Subject</heading>
    <para>
        Choose whether or not to tag the Subject: line of the message if it is
        considered SPAM.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="spam_quarantine">
    <title>General Options: SPAM Quarantine Address</title>
    <heading>SPAM Quarantine Address</heading>
    <para>
        Enter an address to send messages identified as SPAM.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="report_safe">
    <title>General Options: Report Safety</title>
    <heading>Report Safety</heading>
    <para>
        Choose the level of protection/modification done to messages
        marked as spam. At level 0, only the X-Spam-* headers will be
        added to the message.
    </para>
    <para>
        At level 1, the original message will be attached to the report as
        a message/rfc822 part, preserving the original message exactly while
        making it harder to open accidentally.
    </para>
    <para>
        At level 2, the original message will be attached to the report as
        plain text. This provides additional safety for broken email clients
        that open attachments without asking the user, but may make it more
        difficult to access the original message.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="skip_rbl">
    <title>General Options: Skip RBL Checks</title>
    <heading>Skip RBL Checks</heading>
    <para>
        Choose whether or not to check if the sender of the message appears in
        Realtime BlackLists. These lists are not always accurate, and using
        these checks may slow down mail delivery. If your ISP already does
        this, or you do not want to use the RBL, turn this option off.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="skip_virus">
    <title>General Options: Skip Virus Checks</title>
    <heading>Skip Virus Checks</heading>
    <para>
        Choose whether or not to skip virus checks altogether, if allowed by
        system policy.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="skip_spam">
    <title>General Options: Skip SPAM Checks</title>
    <heading>Skip SPAM Checks</heading>
    <para>
        Choose whether or not to skip SPAM checks altogether, if allowed by
        system policy.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="skip_banned">
    <title>General Options: Skip Banned Files Checks</title>
    <heading>Skip Banned Files Checks</heading>
    <para>
        Choose whether or not to skip checking for attachments for banned file
        extensions altogether, if allowed by system policy.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="skip_header">
    <title>General Options: Skip Bad Header Checks</title>
    <heading>Skip Banned Files Checks</heading>
    <para>
        Choose whether or not to skip checking for bad or illegal headers in
        the message, if allowed by system policy.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="allow_virus">
    <title>General Options: Receive Viruses</title>
    <heading>Receive Viruses</heading>
    <para>
        Choose whether or not to allow a message with detected viruses to be
        delivered anyway. This option may not be available due to system
        policy configuration.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="allow_spam">
    <title>General Options: Receive SPAM</title>
    <heading>Receive SPAM</heading>
    <para>
        Choose whether or not to allow a message with detected SPAM to be
        delivered anyway. This option may not be available due to system
        policy configuration.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="allow_banned">
    <title>General Options: Receive Banned Files</title>
    <heading>Receive Banned Files</heading>
    <para>
        Choose whether or not to allow a message with detected banned files
        attached to be delivered anyway. This option may not be available due
        to system policy configuration.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="allow_header">
    <title>General Options: Receive Bad Headers</title>
    <heading>Receive Bad Headers</heading>
    <para>
        Choose whether or not to allow a message with detected bad or illegal
        headers to be delivered anyway. This option may not be available due
        to system policy configuration.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="spam_extension">
    <title>General Options: SPAM Folder</title>
    <heading>SPAM Folder</heading>
    <para>
        Choose a folder to file SPAM into.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="virus_extension">
    <title>General Options: Virus Folder</title>
    <heading>Virus Folder</heading>
    <para>
        Choose a folder to file virus notifications into.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="banned_extension">
    <title>General Options: Banned Files Folder</title>
    <heading>Banned Files Folder</heading>
    <para>
        Choose a folder to file banned files notifications into.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="whitelist_from">
    <title>Whitelist Options: Whitelist From</title>
    <heading>Whitelist From</heading>
    <para>
        Enter a list of sender email addresses from which messages should
        never be identified as SPAM. Put each address on its own line.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="whitelist_to">
    <title>Whitelist Options: Whitelist To</title>
    <heading>Whitelist To</heading>
    <para>
        Enter a list of recipient email addresses to which messages should
        never be identified as SPAM. Put each address on its own line.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="blacklist_from">
    <title>Blacklist Options: Blacklist From</title>
    <heading>Blacklist From</heading>
    <para>
        Enter a list of sender email addresses from which messages should
        always be identified as SPAM. Put each address on its own line.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="blacklist_to">
    <title>Blacklist Options: Blacklist To</title>
    <heading>Blacklist To</heading>
    <para>
        Enter a list of recipient email addresses to which messages should
        always be identified as SPAM. Put each address on its own line.
    </para>
</entry>

<entry id="global_defaults">
    <title>Administrator Options: Make Settings Global</title>
    <heading>Make Settings Global</heading>
    <para>
        If the backend supports it, the administrator can set the options shown
        as site-wide global defaults. Users can still override the global
        defaults with their own settings, but if a user setting is not set,
        the global takes effect. Choose whether or not the displayed settings
        should be applied as the site-wide global defaults.
    </para>
</entry>

</help>
