<?xml version="1.0"?>
<configuration>
 <configsection name="datastore">
  <configheader>Kastalia Datastore Settings</configheader>
  <configstring name="location" desc="The absolute path to the Kastalia Datastore. Default is the directory kastalia/datastore. You can also use a directory outside of the webroot with read-permission for the webserver.">
  /absolute/path/to/horde/kastalia/datastore
  </configstring>
  <configlist name="directoryexcludes" desc="Directories and their content which should not be shown on the download page (lost+found, secretdir, etc.). &lt;strong&gt;WARNING:&lt;/strong&gt; the directories and their content are just hidden on the download page. The Content can still be downloaded by manually modifying the URL." required="false">
  lost+found
  </configlist>
 </configsection>
 <configsection name="upload">
  <configheader>Kastalia Upload Settings</configheader>
  <configboolean name="uploadenabled" desc="Should we enable uploads?">
  false
  </configboolean>
  <configinteger name="maxfilesize" desc="The maximum size (in bytes) of each file that users can upload. &lt;strong&gt;NOTICE:&lt;/strong&gt; the values upload_max_filesize and post_max_size in php.ini have to be greater than or equal to this value.">
  0
  </configinteger>
  <configstring name="tempdir" desc="The absolute path to the Kastalia temporary folder. Default is the directory kastalia/temp. You can also use a directory outside of the webroot with write-permission for the webserver. This temporary folder will be used for the encryption/decryption of uploaded files.">
	  /absolute/path/to/horde/kastalia/temp
  </configstring>
  <configinteger name="tempctime" desc="How long (in minutes) should Kastalia keep a temporary file? Normally a temporary file will be deleted after its use. Because of connection termination or user error during the encryption/decryption an unencrypted temporary file might be stored in the temporary directory. &lt;strong&gt;WARNING:&lt;/strong&gt; a short time can delete a temporary file during the encryption/decryption and will lead to errors. A too long time will delete an unencrypted file late and can lead to a breach of security.">
  10
  </configinteger>
  <configboolean name="securestore" desc="Should we enable Kastalia to store files encrypted? &lt;strong&gt;WARNING:&lt;/strong&gt; This can cause high CPU load by the webserver.">
	  false
  </configboolean>
  <configinteger name="memorysize" desc="The memory size which can be used for the encryption/decryption. This value cannot be greater than the memory_limit value in php.ini. If the value is set too large, you will get a php error message. &lt;strong&gt;WARNING:&lt;/strong&gt; This value is important for the encryption/decryption. If you change this value and you already have files encrypted by Kastalia, these files can only be decrypted with the old memory size value.">
  0
  </configinteger>
  <configinteger name="refreshcycle" desc="The refresh cycle of the browser in seconds during the encryption/decryption. A large value increase the waiting till the encryption/decryption will be done. A small value (and a higher number of users) can lead to many requests to the webserver and slow it down.">
  1
  </configinteger>
 </configsection>
</configuration>
