<?xml version='1.0'?>
<help>

<entry id="fima-overview">
    <title>Fima: Overview</title>
    <heading>What is Fima?</heading>
    <para>
    Fima stands for Finance Manager and is a double entry based ledger. It is a fully flexibel tool for managing your finances including keeping track of your expenses, incomes and assets. It offers creation of budgets, forecasts and a range of different reports for analysis.
    </para>
    <heading>Main features:</heading>
    <para>* free and flexible structure of the table of accounts</para>
    <para>* management and tracking of assets</para>
    <para>* independent posting types: actual, budget, forecast</para>
    <para>* flexible and detailled reports using various parameters</para>
    <para>* graphical report charts</para>
</entry>

<entry id="fima-prefs">
	<title>Fima: Preferences</title>
	<heading>Active Configuration</heading>
	<para>* Your active ledger: select your current ledger</para>
	<para>* Your active posting type: select the current <ref module="fima" entry="postings-postingtypes">posting type</ref></para>
	<para>* Closed by period: select the end of the period until which adding and editing postings will be locked; select &quot;None&quot; to keep all postings changeable</para>
	<heading>Interface Preferences</heading>
	<para>* Postings per page in the list view: enter the number of postings to display per page</para>
	<para>* When displaying the posting, which page do you want to start on: first or last page</para>
	<para>* Sort postings by: select the column which to sort postings by</para>
	<para>* Then: select an alternative column which to sort postings by</para>
	<para>* Sort direction: ascending or descending</para>
	<para>* Select the format for wildcards for text search: DOS wildcards (* and ?), SQL wildcards (% and _) or none</para>
	<para>* Select the format for amounts: select your preferred notation</para>
	<para>* Enter expenses with negative sign: choose whether to omit the negative sign when entering expenses</para>
	<para>* Do you want to confirm deleting postings: choose whether you&apos;d like to confirm deleting postings</para>
	<para>* Select the canvas size for chart reports: the dimensions of the generated image in pixel</para>
</entry>

<entry id="accounts-overview">
	<title>Accounts: Overview</title>
	<para>
	The table of accounts is structured in three levels:
	</para>
	<heading>Account Types</heading>
	<para>
	Account types are the general aggregation of different accounts. Each account is assigned one single type. There are three different account types:
	</para>
	<para>* income (eg. salary, prizes, donations, etc.)</para>
	<para>* expense (eg. food, rental, clothes, etc.)</para>
    <para>* asset (eg. cash, credit card, bankbook, etc.)</para>
    <para>
	It is necessary to specify an asset account for each posting transaction. This way it is possible to track your assets and money transfers as well (postings from an asset account to another one).
	</para>
	<tip>
	Tip: If you are interested in your incomes and expenses only and don&apos;t want to manage any assets, create only one single asset account that will be automatically used for all postings.
	</tip>
	<heading>Account groups, Main Accounts, Subaccounts</heading>
	<para>
	An account is an aggregation of similar types of income, expense or asset positions. An account is defined by its four digit number, a name and an account type. The account number is devided into two parts: XXYY, where XX refers to the account group and YY to the subaccount (eg. in the account group 12: 1200 is the main account, 1230 and 1245 are both subaccounts). It is possible to create 100 account groups each having 100 accounts, whereas the usage of subaccounts is not necessary.
	</para>
	<para>
	Additionally it is possible to save a long description for each account and select whether postings for this account should be marked e.o. by default (see <ref module="fima" entry="postings-overview">Postings Overview</ref>). Also an account may be closed in order to prevent new postings but keep existing ones.
	</para>
	<tip>
	Tip: When using subaccounts avoid posting to the main account XX00, since it won&apos;t be possible to identify these postings in reports when aggregated to account groups. It is recommended to create a separate subaccount for general postings that don&apos;t fit into any subaccount (eg. XX99).
	</tip>
</entry>

<entry id="accounts-delete">
	<title>Accounts: Deleting an Account</title>
	<para>
	When deleting an account you need to specify how to handle postings:
	</para>
	<para>* Delete postings: delete all existing postings that were posted to the specific account</para>
	<para>* Shift postings: move all existing postings to another account of the same account type</para>
	<para>
	Also you need to specify how to handle potential subaccounts and their postings:
	</para>
	<para>* Keep subaccounts and postings: don&apos;t do anything</para>
	<para>* Delete subaccounts and postings: delete all existing subaccounts and postings too</para>
	<para>* Delete subaccounts and shift postings: delete all existing subaccounts and previously shift any existing postings to another account of the same account type</para>
</entry>

<entry id="postings-overview">
	<title>Postings: Overview</title>
	<para>
	A posting record has of the following attributes:
	</para>
	<para>* Posting types: see <ref module="fima" entry="postings-postingtypes">Posting Types</ref></para>
	<para>* Date: date of the posting (day, month, year)</para>
	<para>* Asset account: specifying the asset account for each posting is necessary to track your assets</para>
	<para>* Posting account: the account for the transaction, usually of the type income or expense; when shifting assets (eg. draw cash from an bank account) you need to choose the appropriate asset account as posting account</para>
	<para>* Description: it is possible to enter a short description for each posting (max. 255 characters)</para>
	<para>* Amount: positive amounts increase and negative amounts decrease the chosen asset account</para>
	<para>* e.o.: postings may be marked extraordinary (very large, not planned, ...)</para>
</entry>

<entry id="postings-postingtypes">
	<title>Postings: Posting Types</title>
	<para>
	Each posting is assigned one single type. There are three different posting types:
	</para>
	<heading>Actual</heading>
	<para>
	Actual postings constist of current incomes and expenses which can be analyzed using different reports. It reflects your actual financial situation.
	</para>
	<tip>
	Tip: Always check for asset differences before starting entering new postings. Book any differences to a specific account to guarantee at least correct asset accounts. Also check any bank account statements for missing postings.
	</tip>
	<tip>
	Tip: Try to enter your postings on a regular basis. Always ask for a sales receipt or write down the expense on a piece of paper, so you won&apos;t forget any expenses when not entereing postings immediately.
	</tip>
	<heading>Budget</heading>
	<para>
	Using a budget is optional and offers control of your future financial development as well as analyzing your former financial objectives. This way it is possible to identify your financial scope early.
	</para>
	<tip>
	Tip: Try to follow your main budget objectives. However, don&apos; stick to them at all cost, since there will be incidents that won&apos;t be included in your budget.
	</tip>
	<tip>
	Tip: If you use a detailed table of accounts, create your budget based on main accounts instead of subaccounts since it would be very time-consuming otherwise.
	</tip>
	<tip>
	Tip: Enter any differences between your actual and budget to your budget. This way also your budget assets are up-to-date.
	</tip>
	<tip>
	Tip: It is possible to create your budget based on the postings of the last year by copying and optionally summarize them using the <ref module="fima" entry="postings-transfer">Transfer Postings</ref> functionality and adapting it afterwards.
	</tip>
	<heading>Forecast</heading>
	<para>
	After creating a budget it usually won&apos;t change. All further adaptions can be included in the forecast which therefore is an updated budget.
	</para>
	<tip>
	Tip: Check for any differences between your actual and budget/forecast result regularly and adapt your future forecast.
	</tip>
	<tip>
	Tip: Enter any differences between your actual and forcast to your budget. This way also your forecast assets are up-to-date.
	</tip>
	<tip>
	Tip: It is possible to create your forecast by copying your budget using the <ref module="fima" entry="postings-transfer">Transfer Postings</ref> functionality and afterwards adapting it afterwards.
	</tip>
</entry>

<entry id="postings-addedit">
	<title>Postings: Add/Edit Postings</title>
	<para>
	When adding new postings the date and asset account will be copied from the entry above for convenience, but may be changed later on.
	</para>
	<para>
	Expenses usually are negative amounts, but may be entered without negative sign for convenience (see <ref module="fima" entry="fima-prefs">Interface Preferences: Enter expenses with negative sign?</ref>). However, when shifting assets (transfer from one asset account to another one) the entered value always applies to the selected asset account (eg. -10 means a decrease of the selected asset account by 10 and subsequently an increase by 10 of the asset account selected as posting account).
	</para>
	<tip>
	Tip: When entering new postings, it is possible to select accounts by simply typing the account number on the keyboard instead of browsing through the drop down field. In a short time you will know the most used account numbers and it will save you a lot of time entering new postings.
	</tip>
	<tip>
	Tip: When entering new postings, it is possible to execute mathematical operations in the amount field. Simply type the mathematical expression (eg. 3+2*5) and the result will automatically be calculated.
	</tip>
	<tip>
	Tip: In order to prevent adding or editing postings with a date in the past unintentionally, enter a closing period (see <ref module="fima" entry="fima-prefs">Preferences: Active Configuration: Closed by period</ref>).
	</tip>
	<tip>
	Tip: When entering new postings for <ref module="fima" entry="postings-postingtypes">budget or forecast</ref>, it is possible to automatically create a set of similar postings for each month of a specific year. In the first row enter any date in the desired year, choose an asset and posting account and enter a description (optionally) and amount. Then press the button &quot;Autofill&quot; to copy the entered values down for alle months.
	</tip>
</entry>

<entry id="postings-shift">
	<title>Postings: Shift Postings</title>
	<para>
	Shift several selected postings in order to move them to another posting type or to change the asset or posting account all at once.
	</para>
</entry>

<entry id="postings-transfer">
	<title>Postings: Transfer Postings</title>
	<para>
	Transfer all postings of a specific posting type within a specific period to another posting type using the following options:
	</para>
	<para>* Transfer from: source posting type where to transfer posting from</para>
	<para>* Period from: source period of posting to transfer from</para>
	<para>* Keep original Postings: check to copy selected postings, leave unchecked to move postings</para>
	<para>* Don't summarize: leave postings unchanged</para>
	<para>* Summarize by combining: summarize postings by grouping according to the combination of asset and posting account</para>
	<para>* Summarize by posting against: summarize postings by grouping by asset and posting account seperately, each posting against a specific (dummy) account</para>
	<para>* Transfer to: destination posting type where to transfer posting to</para>
	<para>* Period to: destination period of posting to transfer to</para>
	<para>* Delete existing Postings: previously delete any existing postings of the destination posting type within the destination period</para>
	<tip>
	Tip: You may create a <ref module="fima" entry="postings-postingtypes">budget (or forecast)</ref> by transfering existing posting from actual (or budget). Don&apos;t forget to keep the original posting. It is recommended to summarize postings for a budget (or forecast) to have postings on main account level only. This way it is easier to make adaptions later.
	</tip>
	<tip>
	Tip: It is possible to transfer all postings of a year at once. Select &quot;All&quot; as source and destination month in order to keep the posting month unchanged.
	</tip>
</entry>

<entry id="postings-search">
	<title>Postings: Search Postings</title>
	<para>
	When searching postings it is possible to use the following filters:
	</para>
	<para>* Posting Type: posting type to filter</para>
	<para>* Date Start: start of filter period</para>
	<para>* Date End: end of filter period</para>
	<para>* Asset Accounts: postings with the selected account(s) as asset or posting account (when shifting assets) will be filtered</para>
	<para>* Posting Accounts: postings with the selected account(s) as posting account will be filtered</para>
	<para>* Description: you may use wildcards when search the description (see <ref module="fima" entry="fima-prefs">Interface Preferences: Select the format for wildcards for text search</ref>).</para>
	<para>* Amount Start: minimum amount</para>
	<para>* Amount End: maximum amount</para>
	<para>* e.o. Postings: filter all or none e.o. postings; leave empty to get all postings</para>
	<tip>
	Tip: It is possible to select several asset and posting accounts by holding the shift or control key.
	</tip>
	<tip>
	Tip: When filtering for amounts remember to enter expenses with a negative sign.
	</tip>
	<tip>
	Tip: A search query is saved for the current session until cleaned or a new search is executed. An indicator for an active search query is the trash bin icon located in the header bar.
	</tip>
</entry>

<entry id="reports-overview">
	<title>Reports: Overview</title>
	<para>
	When creating reports it is possible to use the following parameters:
	</para>
	<para>* Report: different <ref module="fima" entry="reports-details">reports</ref></para>
	<para>* Display: select posting type (some reports use the first value only, other use all values)</para>
	<para>* Period: start and end of report period</para>
	<para>* Reference: start and end of report reference period (when using reference as posting type for display)</para>
	<para>* Accounts: postings with the selected account(s) as posting account will be reported</para>
	<para>* Cumulate: summarize partial results within the selected period</para>
	<para>* Subaccounts: additionally show subaccounts instead of main accounts only</para>
	<para>* Null Rows: display rows containing no results</para>
	<para>* Yearly: group results by years instead of months</para>
	<para>* Chart: display a report graph instead of a table view</para>
	<para>
	All reports use only a set of parameters. See <ref module="fima" entry="reports-details">report details</ref> for a description of each report and used parameters.
	</para>
</entry>

<entry id="reports-details">
	<title>Reports: Details</title>

	<heading>General Overview</heading>
	<para>* Description: account types, totals and asset result by posting types</para>
	<para>* Parameters: Display (all), Period, (Reference), Accounts, Chart</para>
	<para>* Chart: bar chart</para>

	<heading>Period Overview</heading>
	<para>* Description: account types, totals and asset result by period</para>
	<para>* Paramaters: Display (first), Period, (Reference), Accounts, Cumulate, Null Rows, Yearly, Chart</para>
	<para>* Chart: line chart</para>

	<heading>Account Overview</heading>
	<para>* Description: posting types by period</para>
	<para>* Parameters: Display (all), Period, (Reference), Accounts, Cumulate, Null Rows, Yearly, Chart</para>
	<para>* Chart: line chart</para>

	<heading>Asset Overview</heading>
	<para>* Description: asset accounts by period</para>
	<para>* Parameters: Display (first), Period, (Reference), Cumulate, Subaccounts, Null Rows, Yearly, Chart</para>
	<para>* Chart: line chart, top 5</para>

	<heading>Analysis</heading>
	<para>* Description: posting types by accounts</para>
	<para>* Parameters: Display (all), Period, (Reference), Accounts, Subaccounts, Null Rows, Chart</para>
	<para>* Chart: pie chart, top 5 (rest grouped) by account type</para>

	<heading>Trend</heading>
	<para>* Description: period by accounts</para>
	<para>* Parameters: Display (first), Period, (Reference), Accounts, Subaccounts, Null Rows, Yearly, Chart</para>
	<para>* Chart: line chart, top 5 by account type</para>
</entry>

<entry id="exemplar-overview">
	<title>Exemplar: Overview</title>
	<para>
	This exemplar demonstrates how to use the main features of Fima. Follow the instructions step by step in the given order.
	</para>
</entry>

<entry id="exemplar-accounts">
	<title>Exemplar: 1) Accounts</title>
	<heading>Asset</heading>
	<para>* 0100 Cash</para>
	<para>* * 0110 Person A</para>
	<para>* * 0120 Person B</para>
	<para>* 0200 Giro</para>
	<para>* 0300 Bankbook</para>
	<para>* 0400 Life Assurance</para>
	<heading>Income</heading>
	<para>* 0000 Opening Balance</para>
	<para>* 1000 Salary</para>
	<para>* 1900 Other Income</para>
	<para>* * 1910 Subsidy</para>
	<para>* * 1999 Miscellaneous</para>
	<heading>Expense</heading>
	<para>* 2000 Food</para>
	<para>* 3000 Home</para>
	<para>* * 3010 Rental</para>
	<para>* * 3020 Electricity</para>
	<para>* * 3030 Furniture</para>
	<para>* 3500 Car</para>
	<para>* * 3510 Insurance</para>
	<para>* * 3520 Fuel</para>
	<para>* 4000 Person A</para>
	<para>* * 4010 Clothes</para>
	<para>* * 4020 Hobby</para>
	<para>* 5000 Person B</para>
	<para>* * 5010 Clothes</para>
	<para>* * 5020 Hobby</para>
	<para>* 9900 Other Expense</para>
	<tip>
	Tip: The table of accounts shown above is only a small example. In reality there are a lot of other things to consider (eg. sales, donations, lottery, interest, TV/Internet, electrical devices, refurbishment, repairings, housekeeping, sanitary products, drugs, pets, coiffeur, car parking, road tax, car mechanic, spare parts, education, telephony, parties, music/video, games, sports, books, smoking, vacation, presents, taxes, etc.)
	</tip>
</entry>

<entry id="exemplar-opening">
	<title>Exemplar: 2) Opening</title>
	<para>
	Before starting to enter regular postings we list our assets and post them against the account 0000 Opening Balance (eg. on the date 2008-01-01):
	</para>
	<para>Asset Account | Posting Account | Amount</para>
	<para>* 0110 Cash - Person A | 0000 Opening Balance | 133.50</para>
	<para>* 0120 Cash - Person B | 0000 Opening Balance | 420.30</para>
	<para>* 0200 Giro | 0000 Opening Balance | -3,412.50</para>
	<para>* 0300 Bankbook | 0000 Opening Balance | 6,850.20</para>
	<para>* 0400 Life Assurance | 0000 Opening Balance | 10,500.00</para>
	<para>In total our asset result is therefore 14,491.50.</para>
	<tip>
	Tip: Use a seperate account of type income for your opening balance. This way reports show correct amounts and assets can be tracked.
	</tip>
</entry>

<entry id="exemplar-postings">
	<title>Exemplar: 3) Postings</title>
	<para>
	After doing our <ref module="fima" entry="exemplar-opening">opening balance</ref> let&apos;s start entering some postings (past the date 2008-01-01):
	</para>
	<para>Asset Account | Posting Account | Amount</para>
	<para>* 0110 Cash - Person A | 2000 Food | -35.00</para>
	<para>* 0110 Cash - Person A | 4020 Person A - Hobby | -22.20</para>
	<para>* 0110 Cash - Person A | 3520 Car - Fuel | -40.00</para>
	<para>* 0120 Cash - Perosn B | 0200 Giro | 1,000.00</para>
	<para>* 0120 Cash - Person B | 2000 Food | -320.10</para>
	<para>* 0120 Cash - Person B | 5010 Person B - Clothes | -278.00</para>
	<para>* 0200 Giro | 1000 Salary | 2,600.00</para>
	<para>* 0200 Giro | 3010 Home - Rental | -520.00</para>
	<tip>
	Tip: The fourth posting is a transaction for shifting assets, person B withdraws 1,000.00 from the giro account. It would have also been possible to look on the transaction from the perspective of the giro account by switching asset and posting account and enter a negative amount.
	</tip>
	<tip>
	Tip: It is possible to enter expenses without negative sign for convenience (see <ref module="fima" entry="fima-prefs">Interface Preferences: Enter expenses with negative sign?</ref>). However, with the fourth transaction (shifting assets) the entered value always applies to the selected asset account.
	</tip>
	<tip>
	Tip: Control the final amounts of asset accounts by using the report <ref module="fima" entry="reports-details">Asset Overview</ref> (with cumulated values).
	</tip>
	<tip>
	Tip: Track and analyse your incomes and expenses using the reports <ref module="fima" entry="reports-details">Account Overview and Analysis</ref>. Use the reports <ref module="fima" entry="reports-details">Period Overview and Trend</ref> to analyse and check the development of costs.
	</tip>
</entry>

<entry id="exemplar-budget">
	<title>Exemplar: 4) Budget</title>
	<para>
	In order to plan and analyze incomes and expenses, we create a budget in 2008 (usually before entering any postings). There are two possibilities for creating a budget:
	</para>
	<para>
	A) Create your budget from scratch by entering postings manually for each month. For convenience it is recommended to use only main accounts. Use the function <ref module="fima" entry="postings-addedit">Autofill</ref> to copy the values from the first line to next eleven for the whole year. It is necessary to enter budget postings for each account seperately this way.
	</para>
	<para>
	B) Create your budget based on incomes and expenses from the last year (if any). Use the function <ref module="fima" entry="postings-transfer">Transfer Postings</ref> with the following parameters:
	</para>
	<para>* Transfer from: Actual</para>
	<para>* Period from: 2007 - All</para>
	<para>* Keep original Postings: yes</para>
	<para>* Summarize Accounts: Summarize by combining.</para>
	<para>* Transfer to: Budget</para>
	<para>* Period to: 2008 - All</para>
	<para>* Delete existing postings: yes</para>
	<tip>
	Tip: Compare budget and actual amounts using the reports <ref module="fima" entry="reports-details">General Overview, Account Overview or Analysis</ref>.
	</tip>
</entry>

<entry id="exemplar-forecast">
	<title>Exemplar: 5) Forecast</title>
	<para>
	Since a budget usually remains untouched after creation, we want a forecast to adapt. There are two possibilities for ceating a forecast:
	</para>
	<para>
	A) Create your forecast from scratch (see <ref module="fima" entry="exemplar-budget">Exemplar: Budget</ref>).
	</para>
	<para>
	B) Create your forecast by copying the budget using the function <ref module="fima" entry="postings-transfer">Transfer Postings</ref> with the following parameters:
	</para>
	<para>* Transfer from: Budget</para>
	<para>* Period from: 2008 - All</para>
	<para>* Keep original Postings: yes</para>
	<para>* Summarize Accounts: Don&apos;t summarize.</para>
	<para>* Transfer to: Forecast</para>
	<para>* Period to: 2008 - All</para>
	<para>* Delete existing postings: yes</para>
	<tip>
	Tip: Compare forecast and budget or actual amounts using the reports <ref module="fima" entry="reports-details">General Overview, Account Overview or Analysis</ref>.
	</tip>
</entry>

</help>
