<?xml version="1.0"?>
<help>
  <entry id="hermes-job-types" state="unknown">
    <title>Tipos de objetos de trabajo/facturables de Hermes</title>
    <heading>Tipos de objetos de trabajo/facturables de Hermes</heading>
    <para>Hermes introduce el concepto de tareas a las que pertenece un periodo de tiempo, as&#xED; como los periodos de tiempo correspondientes a un cliente, aunque  la terminolog&#xED;a utilizada es para una 'objeto de gastos', pero creo que &#xE9;sto puede resultar algo confuso y por ello esta entrada.</para>
    <para>Hermes (as&#xED; parece) presenta posibles objetos de gastos desde m&#xFA;ltiples or&#xED;genes, uno de los cuales son las notas de Mnemo, por lo que si quiere tener una tarea a la que asignar periodos de tiempo, una forma f&#xE1;cil de hacerlo ser&#xED;a crear una nota en Mnemo y asignar los periodos al objeto de gasto representado por la nota.</para>
    <para>Alguien pronto podr&#xED;a desear a&#xF1;adir informaci&#xF3;n sobre otros or&#xED;genes de objetos de gastos. Creo que las incidencias de Whups tambi&#xE9;n se pueden usar como objetos de gastos, pero no estoy seguro.</para>
  <!-- English entry:
<entry id="hermes-job-types">
    <title>Hermes Job Types</title>
    <para>A job type in Hermes characterizes what kind of work has been done
    in a time slice. The administrator has set a number of job types to choose
    from.</para>
  </entry>--></entry>
  <entry id="hermes-cost-objects" state="new">
    <title>Hermes Cost Objects</title>
    <para>Hermes draws possible cost objects from a variety of sources, for
    example deliverable defined by the administator in Hermes, tasks from a
    todo list manager, or tickets from a ticket-tracking system.</para>
  </entry>
  <entry id="hermes-time-format" state="new">
    <title>Hermes Time Format</title>
    <para>Hermes does not format its times as hours and minutes, rather the
    time slices are formatted as decimal portions of an hour.</para>
  </entry>
  <entry id="hermes-submit-slices" state="new">
    <title>Submitting Time Slices</title>
    <para>Submitting time slices "marks" them as finshed. This is
    also a sign for the administrator or bookkeeping department that they are
    ready to be further processed. As long as you didn't submit your slices,
    they are still considered due to be changed, but after submitting them you
    can no longer change them.</para>
    <heading>Submitting Certain Time Slices</heading>
    <para>While this cannot be easily achieved from the default time slice
    view, which shows all time slices for all clients, and the tabs simply
    group the time slices differently, this can be accomplished by using the
    search facility. Set the "Submitted?" field to "No"
    and select any other criteria from the various from fields, then click
    "Search".</para>
    <para>On submission of the search form in that way, you are presented with
    a view just like the initial time slice view, but containing just the
    slices with the picked criteria, with all checkboxes already checked, so
    you can just click "Submit Selected Time" to do so.</para>
  </entry>
</help>
